Sunny: Okay, guys, so let's, start with a class. I hope now I am audible to all of you, yes or no?
Sunny: Okay, great. So, just give me a moment, guys. I'm going to start the session.
Sunny: And my voice is audible.
Sunny: Guys, there is no such echo.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: It's not very useful.
Sunny: I just want to please do that.
Sunny: The church will back down.
Sunny: It's not Someone is saying there's a needle. I don't think so.
Sunny: How is Oracle? Yes or no?
Sunny: Okay, now it is fine, now it is perfect.
Sunny: Great, thank you guys. So let's, begin, let's start with the class. Sorry for the delay, I think we got some delay.
Sunny: Yeah.
Sunny: Actually, my internet was not connecting when I was starting the class, so that's why I started at 8, 2 o'clock, so, sorry for that. Now let's, begin. So guys, first of all, let me give you the quick, recap from the previous classes, and then, basically, let's start with the, new topic.
Sunny: Okay. Sure, Tariq, I'll… I'll do that.
Sunny: 5.
Sunny: The voice is not very low, I think it is fine now on Vova.
Sunny: I can clearly see people are able to hear me, and everyone is saying everything is perfect for them. So please check out from your end if you are facing any such issues.
Sunny: So guys, if you will, look over the dashboard, so there, actually, we have already, completed our fine-tuning chapter. So all the sessions are listed over here, you can see. So I renamed all the sessions. Have you gone through with all the sessions of the fine-tuning?
Sunny: Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: Have you gone through with all the session of the fine-tuning?
Sunny: Okay. That's great, guys. So if you have, seen all the videos of the fine-tuning, then it is fine. If you haven't seen any sort of a video, then definitely you can go through with all the recorded sessions, and you can complete, this particular module. Got it?
Sunny: Now guys, so I've given you one assignment also, related to this fine-tuning module, so have you gone through with that particular assignment?
Sunny: I already uploaded that assignment over the GitHub itself, so once you will go and check over the GitHub, you will find out that assignment. So how many of you, you started that assignment? Can I quickly get into the chat, if you have started that assignment?
Sunny: So this is the assignment, guys, which you will find out inside this folder. So I'm giving you the link of this assignment. If you haven't gone through with this assignment so far, please go through with this assignment, because it is very, very important.
Sunny: So, how to submit this assignment? I think you already know about it. I, have given you each and everything, each and every information related to this assignment. So, just open this docx file, and inside this file, you will get everything. Got it?
Sunny: So let me quickly show you this particular file, and then after, I will come to the new topic.
Sunny: So, where is the assignment? Here is the assignment, guys. This is the assignment, so just open this assignment.
Sunny: Now, after opening this assignment, okay, so please scroll down till the end.
Sunny: It is a very good assignment and very huge assignment as well, so that's why I've given you 2 weeks of time, 50 days of time.
Sunny: And, guys, after that, I will have one demonstration… demonstration session, okay? So there, actually, you can give the demonstration of this entire application, and then, based on that, we'll select the winner.
Sunny: Understood?
Sunny: So let me, show you that. You can implement it using the onslaught, that is completely fine.
Sunny: So, here is all the instruction, how to submit, where to submit, everything you will get over here. What is the submission date? So, today is 4th of July, so by next week, okay? So, sorry, by this week, end of the week, actually, you have to submit this assignment.
Sunny: So, demonstration day is the 12th of July, so there, basically, you will show your application.
Sunny: Now, whoever is going to be, win that competition, right, whoever is going to be a winner, the top 3 winner, okay, so those, folks, basically will get access of this, particular course, the advanced route course.
Sunny: Understood?
Sunny: How much time we have for the demo? So, each person will only take 5 to 10 minutes, okay? Within 10 minutes, basically, they have to complete the demo.
Sunny: That's it.
Sunny: What specifically expected in the demonstration array, Sarathi? Please go through with this assignment. Everything has been mentioned over here.
Sunny: you haven't opened this assignment at least one time, and you are asking. So first, go through with this assignment, and then, if you have any sort of a doubt, you can ask me. Got it?
Sunny: So, if you're going to be submit the assignment, those folks only can give the demonstration. I will get, I will get that, detail inside the Google Sheet only. So, I will call out the name, and you can give the demonstration, and then, basically, you can, select… we can select out the best, possible.
Sunny: Best, basically, demos, okay? And don't worry, don't worry guys, those solutions will be available with you, so anytime you can go with those solutions.
Sunny: Got it?
Sunny: You have to explain the solution only now, right? AWS demo.
Sunny: Please write your exact name. If you are writing any other name, guys, I will not be able to identify you. So please write the correct name while you are joining this session.
Sunny: Now, let's, do one thing, guys. Let's, let me, come to the next module, next topic, which is going to be a RAG, okay? Can we increase the deadline? No, we are not going to increase the deadline. Deadline is clear. Next week only, we have a demonstration. Got it, Sovik?
Sunny: We will get more assignment like this, yes. So you will get 5 to 10 more assignment like this going forward.
Sunny: Can you please answer? Mary is saying, will you accept a KL notebook as I am having issue with the mountaining? Yes, you can, basically do it over the collab also. I don't have any issue. Wherever you are going to do it, whether it's a collab, your own server, your AWS, whenever… wherever you are doing that, do it, okay?
Sunny: If you have office deadline, then, what I can do in that case…
Sunny: You can, do it, via co-pilot, right, Vijay? So, what I can do…
Sunny: Just take some leaves, right, some sick leave or casual leave.
Sunny: You can take that one or two days only. I think within one or two days, you can finish this assignment. I think it won't take more than that, actually.
Sunny: Due date is, Indian time, IST, okay? Indian Standard Time.
Sunny: Great. So now, guys, let's do one thing. Let's start with the session. So guys, today we are going to be start a new chapter. The chapter name is going to be what the chapter name is going to be rag retrieval, argument, generation. Okay, so guys, from here you can be serious. Because here, basically, we are going to be perform like more practical stuff and all.
Sunny: And we are going to be understand the different, different concept of the RAG as well, okay? So, let me, show you the complete RAG pipeline. Let me give you the complete demonstration of the RAG.
Sunny: And then, basically, we'll start with the practical, okay? So, let me revise all the things, whatever we have done so far, and then, basically, I will, come… sorry, then only, basically, I will explain you, this RAG pipeline. So, guys, when, I started this particular course, right?
Sunny: So, let me write a topic or name. So, here I'm going to write that RAG. So, do you know the full form of the RAG? Do you have any idea about the RAG? Have you ever learned about the RAG?
Sunny: Have you ever gone through with this RAG concept?
Sunny: RAG is a very, basically simple topic, but yeah, it is, like, very difficult while we are, implementing it in the real time, okay, in the productionized system, because there are so many moving variables inside the RAG, okay? So we'll understand the RAG, we'll do some project as well. Okay, our project, is going to be based on the RAG only.
Sunny: And we'll understand the different, different concept inside the RAG. Okay, so I will take, again, 8, 6 to 8 classes, or maybe 8 to 10 classes, for this RAG itself. So 2 to 3 week, we'll have a, we'll do the discussion on top of the RAG itself, and even we'll discuss about the.
Sunny: agentic RAG also. So what is the Agentic RAG, and how, basically we can implement that, right?
Sunny: So, let's do one thing, guys, let's start. So, guys, whenever I started this particular course, right, so when I started this course, can anyone tell me when I started this course? What was the date of that?
Sunny: I think everyone knows, right? So, we have started this course at 15th of March.
Sunny: So, there, basically, I discuss about the, what, guys, I discuss about the encoding, embedding, and all, okay? So, we've gone through with all those concepts. Let me write over here, all those topics. So, we discuss about what, guys, we discuss about the…
Sunny: And coding.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: We understood about the embedding.
Sunny: Then, guys, we understood about the transformer architecture. What is a transformer architecture, and how does it work?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Then, guys, we understood how we can access the different, different LLMs, okay?
Sunny: How we can access the different, different LLM. We have seen the different, different architecture based on the transformer, so various LLM architecture.
Sunny: Right? Various LLM.
Sunny: Architecture.
Sunny: So we have gone through with that, right? Then, guys, we have seen the different LLM access APIs, okay? We understood how we can access those specific LLM.
Sunny: Then I enter into the fine-tuning. I explained the different concept of the fine-tuning.
Sunny: And here, we have a lot… we have spent a lot of time, right? Around 8 to 10 classes.
Sunny: And after I took 10 classes, guys, we understood, how to perform the fine-tuning, and what all framework is required for this particular topic. So we spent around 3 months on top of this fundamental. So let me write over here. 3 months around we have spent on top of this fundamental.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Fundamental.
Sunny: So this is all the fundamental, actually, it comes inside the GenAI, okay? Inside the generative AI.
Sunny: Now, we have one more important concept of the GenAI. From there, actually, you will find out most of the practical implementation. So fine-tuning, we are not doing very frequently in the industry. LLM Access API, so again, this is an important topic.
Sunny: Transformer, again, it is an important topic for the fundamental. Encoding embedding, again, it is an important topic. So whatever topic we have learned so far, it was also the important topic.
Sunny: Okay, so, definitely, if you haven't seen those video, recorded lectures are there over the dashboard. Now, the next concept inside the GenAI itself is called the RAG.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: That is a retrieval argument generation. So we'll understand what is a RAG and how we can implement the RAG, right? Now, this concept, actually, it is a little bit different. It is a little bit different from this fine-tuning. It is a little bit different from the training.
Sunny: Because here, basically, the training is not required, okay? We are not going to perform any sort of a training inside,
Sunny: this particular chapter, right? So, inside this particular chapter, basically, we'll mainly focus over the
Sunny: a pipeline, the RAG pipeline, how to build that. Now, if we're talking about the RAG, guys, so we have two main frameworks for implementing the RAG. The first is called the LangChain, and second is called the LangGraph.
Sunny: Right? So LangGraph will come later on when we are going to be develop the advanced variant of the RAG that is called the Agentic RAG. But yeah, we'll use the LangChain as of now, okay? And whenever I'm saying LangChain, LangGraph, so this will be used all together, right? Let's say if I'm going to build a RAG pipeline, so I can build it using the LangChain.
Sunny: Let's say if I'm going to build the Agentic RAG pipeline, or any Agentic kind of thing, or any orchestrator, basically, if I wanted to build, right? So there I will use the LangGraph, right? And along with the LangGraph, I will use the LangGen for reading the model.
Sunny: And for the other sort of stuff, okay? So, we are going to be start a rack, and again, guys, we are going to be spend around 6 to 8 classes on top of the rack.
Sunny: So, first of all, let me explain you about the rack, that what is a rack, what are the components we have inside the rack
Sunny: And then, step by step, one by one, we'll start with the practical, okay? So, first, let's discuss some theoretical points. So, the idea and the agenda is clear. So, I'm assuming 6 to 8 classes.
Sunny: And then again, we have one more bigger chapter, that is Agentic AI. So this RAG and the Agentic AI is two different chapters, okay? So after the RAG, guys, we'll start the Agentic AI chapter.
Sunny: And then we have the other concept also like prompt engineering, evaluation, and then basically guardrails, MCP and all. So that also we can understand. But yeah, these two chapters are the important one. First is the RAG and the second is the Agentic AI. So you need to be more focused on top of this particular chapter. OK, now.
Sunny: let, now let's, start. Now, we're talking about the Agentic AI, guys. So, inside the Agentic AI, again, these two frameworks are the important ones. One is the LangChain, and second is the LangGraph. So, the Agentic, the entire Agentic AI, basically, we can, develop using these two frameworks only.
Sunny: The first is the LangChain and the LangGraph. So, whether we are talking about the RAG or Agentic AI, so, we just required these two frameworks, okay?
Sunny: Now guys, let's do one thing, let's understand about the rack. So guys, the agenda is clear, the idea is clear, you can give me a quick thumbs up if everything is fine so far.
Sunny: Tell me.
Sunny: Yes, we have other framework also, but yeah, these framework are being used a lot, so you will see 95% markets are being captured by this framework only. 95% market are being captured by this framework only. We have some other framework also, it is working in the same way.
Sunny: Now, again, guys, you just required at least one framework to understand the process, to understand the thing, then you can utilize any other framework. And again, guys, I would say.
Sunny: Don't fall into this category, like, where you are going to be, explore the different, different framework, okay? The simultaneously are going to be explore 5 to 6 to 8 framework, okay?
Sunny: It's not at all necessary, it's not at all mandatory.
Sunny: Please understand. Guys, see, I am an Agentic AI engineer. I am a data… sorry, this is a generative AI engineer. From past three years, from past four years, actively, I am working into this particular domain, okay? I am working with this particular technology. Guys, you won't believe I haven't used any other framework than this LangChain and LangGraph.
Sunny: Right? In one of my POC, basically, I have used this, OpenAI SDK. Apart from that, I never touched this CrewAI and the other framework, okay? Other company, other startup and all, they might can… they might use, but again, guys, the concept is the same one.
Sunny: So we have to focus on the fundamental. We have to understand about the concept. Okay? So that's… that's where, guys, I would suggest you, please don't fall into the category where you are going to be explore the multiple framework, but at the end, you are not going to be build anything.
Sunny: Right? You have explored, like, 5 to 6 frameworks. No. Understand one framework, make your, understanding very clear with the one framework itself, develop some good application, okay? And the latter was, simultaneously, you can explore the other framework also. What is the issue with that?
Sunny: What is the issue with that, right? So don't do like… don't do this thing, guys, again.
Sunny: So, guys, are we going to learn this? See, this is not at all required in the industry. I'm an example of it, and even you can ask to any one person.
Sunny: OK, guys, you won't believe I never ever touch the crew AI and the autogen framework. Even I don't know what what is a class in the crew AI which which of the class. But if you will give me the task now I can build the application using the crew AI within a week itself, whether it's a production grade application or any kind of application because my fundamental is very strong related to the Agentic AI. I know the proper orchestration, I know the proper looping.
Sunny: I know the proper tool calling, okay, I know the proper memory management, state management, I have worked onto that site. So I can definitely build this Agentic AI application.
Sunny: Getting my point. So this is a very, like, important advice to all of you, okay?
Sunny: No. So, let's, do one thing, guys. Let's, start, with the rag itself.
Sunny: So guys, if we're talking about the rack, okay, so is this diagram is visible to all of you?
Sunny: Is this, diagram is visible to all of you? So, what is a RAG, guys? So, we're talking about the RAG, okay? So, the full form of the RAG is going to be Retrieval Argument Generation, okay? So, we'll decode this entire diagram, that what is happening over here, what is the meaning of it.
Sunny: Each and every part will understand of this diagram, okay?
Sunny: So, if we're talking about the RAG, guys, okay? So, inside the RAG, basically, you will find out 3 terms. Let me write over here.
Sunny: We were talking about the rat, so there, you will find out the three terms.
Sunny: The first is going to be what? The first is going to be retrieval.
Sunny: Okay. The second is going to be augmentation.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: And the third is going to be generation.
Sunny: So just pick, the first word of this, particular, the first… pick the first character of this particular word.
Sunny: So, here we have this R.
Sunny: Now you can see the R.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: The second is going to be A.
Sunny: And the third is going to be G. So here we have this R.
Sunny: The second is going to be A. The third is going to be G. Okay? So from here only, you will find out this particular term that is called the RAG.
Sunny: Got it, guys. Now, what is the meaning of it, what we are doing over here? Let's try to understand that one. So, guys, here you can see this particular architecture, and even I written something over here, over the blackboard.
Sunny: So RAG is what? RAG basically gives the relevant context to the LLM before answering, okay? So this is the entire idea behind the RAG. If someone is going to be asking you that what is a RAG, so you can say.
Sunny: It gives the relevant context to the LLM before answering, okay? Now, if we're talking about the RAG, guys, so this RAG, basically, we can divide into two main pipe… two main parts. The first is called the ingestion and the indexing. The second is called the retrieval and the generation, okay?
Sunny: Now, we have 3 main components. I will discuss those components of the RAG, okay, but as of now, let's divide this particular pipeline into 2 main parts. The first is going to be ingestion, and the second is going to be what? Retrieval in the generation. Now, inside this diagram, guys, can you see? So, inside this particular diagram, guys, can you see the LLM?
Sunny: Is the LLM visible to all of you? Tell me.
Sunny: So, inside this particular diagram, you can see the LLM. So, here we have the LLM, okay?
Sunny: Here, basically, what we have, we have the LLM. Now, guys, let's say, this is my LLM. Let me take the LLM. This is what, this is my LLM.
Sunny: Now we can give the input to the LLM.
Sunny: You can give any sort of input to the LLM.
Sunny: And we can generate the response.
Sunny: Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: We can give the input to the LLM, and we can generate the response out of the LLM.
Sunny: Now, this is called the simple, generation, or this is called the simple AI assistant. Now, if we're talking about the RAG, guys, so inside the RAG, basically, we are giving a more context, we are giving a more context to the LLM.
Sunny: Okay? Now, why we are giving that, what is our, like, idea behind that, okay, why it is required, everything we are going to be discussed. So, guys, we can give the simple input to the LLM, okay, and we can generate the output. But, guys, if we're talking about the RAG pipeline, so inside the RAG pipeline, we are not giving this input directly.
Sunny: So we are augmenting this particular input.
Sunny: We are augmenting this particular input.
Sunny: Okay? Argumenting.
Sunny: Okay, after the augmentation, only we are giving this input to where we are giving info to the Llm. Now, if I'm saying augmentation guys or augmenting the input, so what is the meaning of it? The meaning is very, very simple. So we are adding the more context to the input. Okay, because my Llm. Basically, it does not know everything.
Sunny: It's not having each and every information, so that's why what we are doing, we are adding the more context inside the input. Now, this is what is my input prompt, and then we are passing to the LLM, and then only the LLM is going to generate the final response, okay? So here, guys, you can see, so.
Sunny: We're talking about the RAG, okay? So I can write the three main components of the RAG over here. The first component of the RAG is going to be what?
Sunny: The first component of the RAG is going to be
Sunny: Tell me, guys, what it is. It is called the data parsing.
Sunny: Okay? It's a very important component of the RAG, that is called the data parsing. The second component of the RAG is called what, guys? It is called the data ingestion.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: data ingestion.
Sunny: The third component of the RAG is going to be what?
Sunny: Retrieval.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Retrieval. And, see guys, what I can do, I can write like this, so just a second.
Sunny: So, I can write the data ingestion, and the data parsing, basically, it could be part of that, okay? So, let me rewrite this one. So, we're talking about the first component, so that is called what? That is called the data ingestion.
Sunny: Right? Data ingestion.
Sunny: Now, we're talking about the RAG, guys, so this data ingestion, is one of the components, and here, guys, the very important concept comes, that is called the data parsing. So let me write what? Let me write this, the extended one of it, that is called the data parsing, okay?
Sunny: So here, basically, we are going to be parse the data, and then we are going to be stored it where, inside the vector database. Now, we have to do one more thing over here. The data parsing, basically, it is also called the document AI.
Sunny: Okay? So we'll understand what is a document AI, and, definitely we'll try to perform that. The second is called what, guys? The second is called what? The second is called the, retrieval. Okay?
Sunny: Retrieval.
Sunny: So here, basically, what we do, we retrieve the data, okay? And the third is called what? The third is called the…
Sunny: Generation. Okay?
Sunny: Third is what, guys? Third is called the generation. So the first is called the data ingestion. This data parsing, document AI, actually, it is a part of the data ingestion only.
Sunny: Where we are going to retrieve the data from the different, different document, and we are going to be stored where inside the vector databases, okay? So again, databases, vector databases, it is a part of the data ingestion only.
Sunny: The second is called the retrieval. It is a very important part of the RAG, okay, and the third is called the generation. Now, we're talking about the difficulty level, so this data parsing, basically, this data parsing and the retrieval, basically, it is a difficult one. Difficult one means what if you are working in the production, guys, production system.
Sunny: And we are working in the real-time project, so this, thing we have to do very, very carefully, okay? Now, here, basically, we have to fetch the data.
Sunny: Okay, fetch the data, and after fetching the data, guys, what we have to do, we have to arrange the data, okay? So, fetching the data, arranging the data, it's a very typical task, right? We have very huge data. If the data is very scalable, right? In that case, this task is going to be very, very typical, right?
Sunny: And the second is called the retrieval. Again, to retrieve the correct information, okay?
Sunny: to retrieve the correct information, it's a very important thing. So the accuracy of the retrieval component is a very, very important. Generation side is not very difficult, so here we just have to be… here we just have to play with the prompt, okay? And then, basically, we just have to use the bets to best LLM.
Sunny: So if you are going to be use the best to best LLM at this particular place, then my answer is going to be quite good, right? So if we're talking about the RAG, guys, so inside the RAG, basically, you will find out difficulty at these two places. The first is going to be a data passing, that is called the document AI, or that is called the data ingestion. Okay, it's a part of the data ingestion only.
Sunny: The second is called what? The second is called the retrieval, okay? And the third is what, guys? Third is the generation.
Sunny: Now, if you will look into this particular diagram, guys, so inside the diagram, I have mentioned the same thing, okay? So, is it visible to all of you? Now, tell me, guys, are you enjoying this RAG1?
Sunny: Is it clearly, visible, or it is clearly understandable or not? Yes or no?
Sunny: Now, guys, the next is going to be what? So let's understand, this particular diagram, okay? So what is indexing, what is this, that, okay? Everything we are going to be understand, don't worry about it. Even I will, like, show you the advanced pipeline, where we are going to be integrate the memory, caching.
Sunny: Evaluation, guardrails, everything we will implement inside the same pipeline itself. But first, let's talk about the… first, let's talk of the classical pipeline of the RAG, okay?
Sunny: First, let's have a discussion onto this classical pipeline. So, guys, let's suppose we have a document, or we have a data. Okay, let's start from here.
Sunny: So, we have our data, guys. Now, after that, what we do, we perform the chunking of the data, okay? What we do, guys, we perform the chunking of the data, and we perform the embedding of the data. Now, guys, this chunking, actually, it is an optional step.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Even you can skip this particular step, this particular step is not even required, this chunking step, okay? So, here we have our data, then we are going to be collect the data, we are going to be store this data where
Sunny: After the embedding, guys, we are going to be stored this data inside the vector databases. So this, particular database is actually, it's a special database, okay, which is designed for storing the embedding only.
Sunny: So we're going to be using different databases, okay? I'll show you how to use the vector database, and how to store the data inside. Got it? So, this is… this particular process is called what? This particular process is called the data ingestion.
Sunny: From where? From, document, from data, to the chunking, to the embedding, to the vector databases, right? Now, guys, after that, guys, what happened? See, whenever we are getting any sort of a query, so let's say here is my user, or whoever is writing that query, so we are not directly passing that query to the LLM, okay?
Sunny: So we are not directly passing that query where to the LLM.
Sunny: Now, instead of that, what we are doing, instead of that, basically, we are going to be passed that particular query to where? To the vector database, okay? So we are going to be performed the embedding of that query, alright, and we are passing it to the vector database, where we'll perform the similarity search operation, right? And then we are going to be figured out the chunk.
Sunny: Now, this particular process is called the retrieval, right?
Sunny: So this is called what? This is called the retrieval. This is the retrieval process, where basically we are going to retrieve the data, okay? So this is what, guys, this is the retrieval process.
Sunny: Then after that, guys, what we are doing, so we are providing the prompt, okay? We are providing the context, okay? Means, here, basically, we have the prompt, some additional instruction.
Sunny: The context, basically, which we are going to be retrieved from the database, okay? Let me write over here what we have over here, guys. So here we have a prompt, some additional instruction, the context, basically, which we are going to be retrieved from the database, okay? And then the query, basically, right? So, we are going to be combined all this thing, and we are passing this particular information to the LLM.
Sunny: And then only LLM is going to be generated the final answer. So this particular process is called the generation. So how many process we have over here? The first process is called the data ingestion. The second is called what? The second is called the retrieval. This red one is called the retrieval.
Sunny: And the third is called what? Third is called the generation, okay? Now, guys, here, basically, we have the vector database. Nowadays, maybe you are hearing the new term that is called the vector-less, RAG, right?
Sunny: So, you can basically skip this vector database. Directly, you can retrieve the information from this document itself, right? So, it is just a traditional way of retrieving the information. Now, again, guys, vector-less data… vector-less RAG is not a magic.
Sunny: Right? It might work, it might not work. Okay, it might give you the good accuracy, it might give you the less accuracy. So you will have to test on that. I have read out the different different blog, the different different basically solution and all I have went through. So I have figured out that vector less rag is not a magic, it is just a traditional technique where we are directly going to be retrieve the information from the document itself based on the keyword, based on the
Sunny: Basically BM25 retriever based on some other kind of sources, OK? And then directly we are passing it to the LLM. That's it. That is just a classical way of building a rag, OK? So you might get a good accuracy most of the time inside the vector database of via vector database, basically vector based rag instead of the vector less rag.
Sunny: So vector less rag actually it might work in some of the use cases, but again it is not a solution. OK, it is not a replacement of the vector based rag. Got it. So even I will show you how you can perform the vector less rag also. I'll show you one solution around to that. Making sense to all of you? Tell me yes or no. Is it getting clear?
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Yes, we'll discuss each and everything, so here I kept all the, use cases and all everything, okay? So I just started, Ramanath, let me go through with this entire slide, everything you will get over here, right?
Sunny: Now, why it is optional? Because the chunking is not required every time, okay? Chunking is not required every time. Now, what is the meaning of the indexing, guys? Indexing is nothing, so whenever we are going to be store our data inside the vector database.
Sunny: So that is only called the chunking. Sorry, that is only called the indexing, okay? So we are going to be store… we are going to be store the data inside the vector database in the form… in the form of indexing, okay? In the form of indexes.
Sunny: So, when I will, come to the practical, guys, in… at that time, you will, understood, that, thing very, very clearly, okay? So, I will show you each and everything in terms of practical. Got it?
Sunny: Great. So guys, over here, see, if we're talking about the RAG, so what is the definition, the classical definition of the RAG?
Sunny: So let's read out the classical definition of the RAG. Here I mention, RAG is a technique that helps an LLM answer question, okay?
Sunny: using the external data, such as PDF, document, website, databases, or company knowledge base. So from wherever, from whichever place you can take a data, okay, from any place you can take the data, you can retrieve the context out of that data, you can provide that context to the LLM,
Sunny: And then behalf on that, LLM can generate the answer, okay? So guys, if we're talking about the RAG, so how we are going to be understand the RAG, let me, basically write all the points over here, just a second.
Sunny: So first, guys, we'll understand what is a RAG. I think most of the people are able to understand that, what is a RAG, okay? I'll give you a couple of more examples, so the idea will be more clear.
Sunny: So the first thing is what? First thing is, what is our rack?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: The second thing, basically, why RAG?
Sunny: Why? RAG is required.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: The third, basically, third is what? Third is going to be RAG.
Sunny: Pipeline.
Sunny: So, already I've shown you the RAG pipeline. Again, I will discuss onto that, and each and everything I'll show you in the practical.
Sunny: So, as we are going to be proceed, guys, so I will show you some advanced RAG pipeline also. Okay, so we'll see some advanced RAG pipeline also, where we are going to be integrate everything inside our RAG pipeline, whether it's a memory, okay, and the different other concept of the RAG.
Sunny: And the different other concert, basically, which comes for the rag, okay? Which comes under the rag.
Sunny: Then guys, this fourth one is going to be what? The fourth is going to be RAG versus fine-tuning. So we'll discuss what is a RAG versus fine-tuning. I already capped that thing.
Sunny: Okay, RAG versus fine-tuning. So I… I will just definitely discuss of this RAG versus fine-tuning. So these are the points, basically, which we are going to be discussing, if we're talking about the introduction of the RAG.
Sunny: And then, basically, we'll come to the first component of the practical implementation. That is going to be a data parsing.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: That is going to be what? That is going to be a data parsing. Now, this data parsing, basically, it is a part of what? It is a part of the data ing
Sunny: So it is a part of what? It is a part of the data ingestion. So first, we'll understand the data parsing inside the data ingestion. Let me write the one over here. Okay, so we'll discuss what is the data parsing, how to perform the data parsing. That is also called the document AI. Okay, so I'll show you some model.
Sunny: Which is able to retrieve the data from the different, different document and all. Then after that, guys, we'll understand about what.
Sunny: We'll understand about the, this one, vector databases, okay?
Sunny: vector databases, how to keep the data inside a vector databases. Now, chunking and the embedding, actually, it is going to be part of that only.
Sunny: So chunking and embedding, it is going to be part of that only.
Sunny: we'll understand about the vector database. So these two main concepts will be there with respect to the data pa… with respect to the data ingestion. The first is going to be data parsing, and the second is going to be vector databases, right? So in this particular flow, we are going, okay? So we'll follow this flow in the next three to four classes.
Sunny: The next concept will come, that is called the retrieval pipeline. So we'll work on the retrieval pipeline.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So we'll work on the retrieval pipeline. The different, different retrieval pipeline technique we'll
Sunny: Okay, what is a similarity search and all, everything we'll see over here. Even though we have already learned it in our previous classes, but again, I'll show you that. And then, guys, the third is going to be what? The third is going to be a generation one.
Sunny: So let me write over here. The third is going to be what? The third is going to be a generation. So here, basically, we'll, definitely discuss about what? We'll definitely discuss about the prompt technique and all.
Sunny: So, I will show you the prompt chapter, I will discuss the prompting technique and all everything over here, okay? So, likewise, guys, we are going to be proceeding inside the RAG pipeline, in the… inside the RAG module, in the RAG chapter, and in this particular way only, in this particular manner only, we'll be discussing that.
Sunny: Making sense to all of you, yes or no?
Sunny: Tell me.
Sunny: Okay? So let's, discuss the first point, that what is a RAG, okay?
Sunny: So, guys, here, if we are talking about
Sunny: The rag. Okay, what is the rag, guys? Tell me
Sunny: Can anyone tell me what is a rack?
Sunny: RAG stands for… RAG stands for what? RAG stands for Retrieval Argument Generation, okay?
Sunny: Now, retrieval means what? We are talking about the retrieval, guys. So, the finding relevant information from the document, okay?
Sunny: finding relevant information from the document, that is called what? That is… that is called the retrieval, right? Now, we're talking about the augmentation. So, what is the augmentation, guys? Adding that retrieval information is an extra context to the user question. So, whatever user is asking, guys.
Sunny: Okay? To that user question, what we are doing, we are going to be at the extra context, and this extra context is nothing. It is just that retrieve information. Okay?
Sunny: It is just bot, it is just the retrieve information. Now, here I written the separate definition of the augmentation also, because here people are having some confusion. So, augmentation is nothing, it is, improving the LLM input.
Sunny: Okay, whatever input we are providing to the Llm. Right? So improving the Llm. Input by adding the retrieve context. So that's the meaning of the augmentation. Now, the final one is going to be what final one is going to be generation. So Llm. Generate the final answer using that particular context. So all these 3 terms are clear to all of you. Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: I will show you more example and, after that guys, everything is going to be clear, ok so, tell me guys, if this part is clear to all of you, yes or no.
Sunny: Tamiyas?
Sunny: I want yes or no from everyone's side. If you are saying no, then if your answer is no, then please write no, okay?
Sunny: Great, guys. So, I hope everyone is able to understand that now.
Sunny: Now, over here, guys, see?
Sunny: No.
Sunny: this is the example, guys, right? So let's understand with this particular example, your most of the part is going to be clear, right? So…
Sunny: Here, guys, you can see.
Sunny: Let's say a user is asking some question. So let's say I have a question, what is the refund policy of our company?
Sunny: Now, this… the LLM may not know this, because company policies are private data, okay? So, let's say we are using one LLM.
Sunny: The LLM name is what? Let's say the LLM name is OpenAI.
Sunny: Sorry, GPT-5, okay?
Sunny: So I'm using this GPT 5.5 model.
Sunny: Now, let's say I'm asking what is the refund policy of the… what is the refund policy of our company, right? Let's say I'm asking about this Krishnaik Academy.
Sunny: Now, tell me, guys, this GPT 5.5
Sunny: It knows about this, it knows about this particular information, the refund policy and all.
Sunny: So while they were training this particular data, while they were training this particular model, okay, maybe they haven't included this particular information, right? Now, if you will check with the ChatGPT also, if you are asking to the ChatGPT, so what this ChatGPT is doing, you know, it is doing a web search.
Sunny: So, from where it is, picking the context.
Sunny: From where it is picking the context, guys. So it is picking the context from where.
Sunny: It is picking the context from the internet, okay?
Sunny: it is picking the concert from the internet, and then only it is answering. Let's say if you're asking to the ChatGPT, let's say if you're asking to the ChatGPT,
Sunny: what is the current temperature in Bangalore, okay?
Sunny: Current?
Sunny: Temperature.
Sunny: In Bangalore.
Sunny: Now, guys, ChatGPT is not trained on top of this, sorry, the GPT model which is being used inside the ChatGPT application. Now, first of all, you will have to understand this ChatGPT is an application.
Sunny: Okay? And guys, this, the model, basically, which is being used.
Sunny: the model, basically, which is being used inside the ChatGPT, right? So, just a second.
Sunny: Okay. So… yeah. So the model, basically, which is being used inside a chat GPT, right? This one. So that is what that is, a GPT 5.5.
Sunny: And this is a transformer-based model.
Sunny: This is what is the transformer-based model.
Sunny: which have been trained on some sort of a data, alright? This one.
Sunny: So maybe it is not up-to-date with the latest information, or the latest knowledge. So what it will do, guys, so here, we're talking about… we are asking to the ChatGPT, what is the current temperature in the Bangalore, so it will do the web search.
Sunny: it will do the web search to fetch out the actual information. And then it will retrieve the context from the web search only.
Sunny: It's going to be retrieve the context, it's going to be, it's going to be, like, take that context from the web search, via web search, it's going to be take a real-time information from there.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: And then only it's going to be generate the answer. Now guys, let's say if you are going to be build your application, your company's specific application, so this LLM don't know about, LLM don't know basically about your refund policy, okay? So here what it will do, so RAG, what it does actually, it search the company's policy document.
Sunny: It retrieves the relevant refund policy section from there. It adds that retrieve section as an extra context to the user question, and then it gives to the LLM, okay, context question, and some additional prompt and all, right?
Sunny: some additional instruction, okay? So, context question, everything is being provided to the LLM, and then LLM generate the final answer based on the document, okay? Based on that particular context. Getting my point, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: Is it getting clear? So this is the example, basically, which is being used by every sort of a company. So let me write over here, context.
Sunny: So based on that particular context, which we are retrieving from the document, it is going to generate the correct answer.
Sunny: So let's say, LLM, sorry, the user is asking a question, what is our refund policy? Now, retrieve context is a refund are allowed within 7 days of the purchase. Okay, these are retrieve contexts based on this particular question. Now, this particular retrieve context we are getting from the similarity search.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: Similarity search. Now, the similarity search is nothing is one of the mathematical operation.
Sunny: I think you already know about it, what is a similarity search, I already discussed in my previous classes, right?
Sunny: It is a mathematical operation. So based on that, we are going to be fetch this retrieve context. Then we are going to be augment the prompt. So here is my prompt, what is a refund policy? Along with that, we are adding this context. Okay. Now this final thing is going to the LLM. This final thing, we are passing it to the LLM.
Sunny: Okay? If I have to add some more instruction, then I can add those instruction also. Okay? Some custom instruction I can provide to the LLM. Then I'm passing it to the LLM, and then LLM is generating the final answer.
Sunny: So this is only called the augmentation of the information.
Sunny: This is only what, guys, this is only called the augmentation of the information.
Sunny: Is it getting clear or not?
Sunny: Is this part getting clear?
Sunny: So to implement this entire practical, it is only called the RAG pipeline. This is only called the RAG pipeline.
Sunny: Whatever we are learning over here, this is only called the RAG pipeline.
Sunny: Now, here, guys, you can see. So, this is the, like, in short, I have written everything. LLM do not have access of the latest information, okay?
Sunny: We retrieve the relevant context from the document, from the databases, from the web, from wherever we can retrieve that information. We give the LLM context of the question, okay, to the LLM, and then LLM gives the final and the grounded answer.
Sunny: Making sense to all of you? If this part is clear, then please let me know in the chat. And the information we can retrieve from anywhere, we can retrieve from any of the places. Okay? So if this part is clear, you can let me know in the chat so that I can proceed, guys. Fast.
Sunny: If you're getting it, then please let me know.
Sunny: I know.
Sunny: Sunil, please wait, okay? Each and everything will be clear, because you are learning the RAG first time, it will take some time, right? So just give me half an hour, half and more hour, everything will be clear. Got it?
Sunny: Everyone is able to understand? Now, let's do one thing, guys. Let's understand a couple of more things. Now, why this RAG is required?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: why the RAG is required. So we use a RAG, so here I've written the clear-cut detail. We use a RAG because normal LLMs have some limitations.
Sunny: So the first thing is, basically, the first problem with the LLM is what? Here you can see the first problem. The first problem, basically, LLM do not have any private data, okay?
Sunny: LLM is not… have been trained on some private data. Private data means what? I can give you the better example. So, let's say we have some XYZ company, right?
Sunny: some XYZ company.
Sunny: Now, let's suppose this is a pharma company.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: This is a pharma company.
Sunny: So whatever data is being used inside the pharma company, whatever data they are keeping in some databases, wherever, basically, right? So this is the, guys' proprietary data, their proprietary data, okay? So this data set is not being used while they were training this GPT-5.
Sunny: Or any other model, let's say cloud model.
Sunny: Or let's say Gemini model Okay.
Sunny: Because this data, actually, it's a private data.
Sunny: It's a red data.
Sunny: Okay, it's their proprietary data.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: It's their proprietary data.
Sunny: Okay? So guys, this dataset is a private data, and LLM is not having the information, okay? LLM is not having the information from this particular data. So if I will ask any question related to this data inside this company, let's say, inside this particular company, I wanted to build one chatbot.
Sunny: Chatbot.
Sunny: Using this GPT-5 model.
Sunny: And if I'm going to be asked any question related to this data, in that case, it will not be able to answer, because GPT-5 model is not being trained on top of this particular data.
Sunny: So what we do, guys, we build the RAG pipeline.
Sunny: We provide some additional context from this particular data to the model, to this GPT model, and then behalf on that particular context only, the LLM is going to generate the answer. So this is the first thing.
Sunny: But why we are going to be build this RAG pipeline, okay, why the RAG is required. The second is what? The second is, again, the LLM may not have the latest data. Again, this is the big concern, right?
Sunny: LLM is not having any latest data, okay? LLM is not having the latest information. In that case, we are providing that latest information in the form of context.
Sunny: And behalf on that, only LLM is generating the final answer. The third thing is a very important thing. I think you have heard about this particular problem statement. That is called the hallucinations, okay?
Sunny: Hallucination is a very big problem in the industry, okay, at anywhere, basically, and because of that also, we build this rack, right? So what is the hallucination, guys? Let's understand about it.
Sunny: So, here, I written the definition of the hallucination. If someone is going to be asked in an interview, I think you can clearly explain about it, what is a hallucination. So, hallucination is nothing. Hallucination means, sometime, LLM is going to be generated the confident but the wrong answer.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So this is what… this is called the hallucination.
Sunny: So, RAG reduces the hallucination because the answer is based on the retrieve context. So, we are going to provide some additional context, and because of that only, RAG is reducing the hallucination. So, let's look into the example. Let's say, user is asking, what is the refund policy of the ABC company?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Guys, you are getting it now, yes or no? Tell me.
Sunny: Yes? Okay. So, here, guys, let's say user is asking what is the refund policy of the ABC company. Now, without RAG, LLM is confidently saying what LLM is saying. Now, read over here. LLM is saying ABC company offer 30-day refund policy.
Sunny: But in actual company document, the policy says, refund policy allowed only within 7 days, okay? So if LLM is giving the confident but the wrong answer, so that is what that is called the hallucination. And this is a very, impo- this is a very, like, huge problem, in the industry, okay?
Sunny: LLM might give some hallucinated answer, and because of that only, what we do, guys, we use the RAG. I think many of you, you heard about this hallucination. Yes or no? Tell me.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: Many of you, you know about these hallucinations, correct?
Sunny: many of you, you know about this hallucination, and I think so. This is a very critical thing in the industry, okay?
Sunny: Now, coming to the next part. So, here, guys, you can see the problem 4. The problem 4 is the fine-tuning. Means, fine-tuning is not always the right solution.
Sunny: Okay? We always cannot do the fine tuning.
Sunny: So for every new document, we cannot fine-tune the model again and again.
Sunny: And where the rag is a better when the data is changing very, very frequently.
Sunny: Right? If HR policy change every month, every day, every week, so why should we do the fine-tune of the model?
Sunny: And fine-tuning is an expensive process also. So what we do, guys, we take the advantage of the reasoning capability of the LLM, and based on that only, we are going to generate some answer. Because nowadays, LLMs are the enough intelligent one, correct?
Sunny: Nowadays, LLMs are the enough intelligent ones. So we take the advantage of the reasoning capability of the LLM, we provide some additional context to the LLM, and based on that only, we are going to generate the final answer. So the fourth one is going to be what? What is the fourth point, guys? Tell me. The fourth point, basically.
Sunny: This is the fourth point, guys, this one.
Sunny: So, problem fine-tuning is not always a right solution. And because of that.
Sunny: What we do, guys? We do the RAG.
Sunny: So if someone is going to be ask you that why we have to, create a RAG pipeline, why the it is required, so will you be able to explain to that person? Tell me yes or no?
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: So if someone is going to be asked you why the drag is required, will you be able to answer?
Sunny: Yes, I think you can easily answer that, correct? Now, guys, coming to the next one. So, we're talking about the RAG pipeline. So, this is the complete RAG pipeline, okay? So, this is the complete RAG pipeline. I think already I have shown you this particular RAG pipeline. Now, again, let me give you the quick recap of it.
Sunny: So guys, if we're talking about the RAG pipeline, so these are the important components of the RAG pipeline.
Sunny: The first is called the source document.
Sunny: Or the source data.
Sunny: The second is called the chunking. It is an optional one. We can skip this part. Then, embedding.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Then what, guys, embedding is an important concept of the RAG pipeline. The third one is going to be a vector store.
Sunny: The next is going to be water retrieval, okay? Then generation, and then finally user means the final output, right?
Sunny: So we'll understand the type of the chunking. Each and everything, guys, will understand over here. Don't worry. As we will progress, each and every part is going to be clear. So let me explain you this pipeline one more time.
Sunny: I can draw it over here.
Sunny: So, guys, let's suppose… okay, guys, again, I'm going to redraw that pipeline. Wait we have the LLM.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, here is my user.
Sunny: This is what is my user, guys.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: User is asking a question to the LLM. User is giving some prompt to the LLM, user is trying to ask something to the LLM.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: User is having a question.
Sunny: And it want the answer from where? From the LLM. Okay?
Sunny: the output.
Sunny: Now, guys, tell me, this is what we are doing inside the rack?
Sunny: Yes or no?
Sunny: This is what we are doing inside the rack.
Sunny: No, guys. This is not what we are doing inside the rack.
Sunny: This is completely… No.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: No, we are not doing it.
Sunny: Not… we are not doing this inside the rack.
Sunny: So, how to design the RAG pipeline?
Sunny: How to design the RAG pipeline.
Sunny: So first, guys, this user question, whatever user question we have, right?
Sunny: This particular user question… This particular user question.
Sunny: We'll go where? Tell me, guys. This will go to the vector database.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: This particular user question is going where? To the vector database. Now here, we are going to be perform the embedding of this particular question.
Sunny: Okay? Now, this is what is my vector database.
Sunny: Now, inside this vector database, we have already stored our data.
Sunny: We have already stored our data in the form of what? In the form of vector.
Sunny: Okay? So what we'll do, guys, we'll… this particular question is going into the vector database, okay? It's going to be connect… it's going to be interact with the vector database, and then it's going to be retrieve some information.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So this is what, guys, this is called the retrieval.
Sunny: Now this retrieval actually it is happening based on what? Based on the similarity search.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: this information. Now, this information is called what? This information is called the context.
Sunny: Right? So guys, now what we have, we're talking about what we have. So we have three things. First is a user question.
Sunny: Second is the context, that is my retrieve information.
Sunny: And the next, basically, we have some custom instruction that I can say as a prompt.
Sunny: Or this is only the user prompt, now we can write some custom instruction also.
Sunny: Custom instruction.
Sunny: Do this, do that, something like this. Okay? Now, this is only called what? This is only called the augmentation.
Sunny: This is only called what? This is called the augmentation.
Sunny: Where we are enriching this user question, Just by adding some context.
Sunny: Okay? And reaching this user question just by adding the context, right? Then, guys, this particular information… this particular information is going to the LLM.
Sunny: This particular information is going where? This particular information is going to the LLM.
Sunny: Okay? Now, LLM is generating a finer output.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So this is called what? This is called a generation.
Sunny: This is called the augmentation. This is called the retrieval.
Sunny: Okay? Now, guys, if we're talking about this vector database, so how we are going to be… how we are going to be initiate this vector databases? So this is the vector databases we are going to be initiate based on the data sources.
Sunny: So this is my raw data sources.
Sunny: raw data sources.
Sunny: Now, these data sources could be anything. It could be my PDF document.
Sunny: It could be my docx document.
Sunny: It could be my internal DB.
Sunny: It could be my… any sort of a DB, whatever DB, basically, we have. It could be Vector Web Internet. It could be the…
Sunny: Internal portal.
Sunny: It could be any cloud artifactory.
Sunny: Cloud Artifactory.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Whatever is coming in your mind, guys, you can think about that. It is a data source.
Sunny: Now, we are going to be extract the information from this data source.
Sunny: This is called the data parsing.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: This is called what, guys? This is called the data parsing. Making sense or not, guys? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: Now, we are going to retrieve the data. This is called what? This is called the data parsing. Any kind of data it could be. It could be any unstructured data, audio, video, whatever, guys, whatever, right? Audio, images, video.
Sunny: on whatever data you wanted to build a RAG, it could be the data source, right? So we're going to be extract the data. Now here, guys, two more steps come, see?
Sunny: Here, guys, the chunking. Chunking means what? Chunking means…
Sunny: to divide the data into the small, small pieces. I will discuss on… or I will discuss this thing, don't worry.
Sunny: So, chunking is nothing. Divide the data into small pieces, okay? Data.
Sunny: Into… is small.
Sunny: Pieces.
Sunny: Okay? Then, guys, we are going to be stored this data inside where? Inside the vector database. Now, can you tell me, guys, can we directly store this data inside the vector databases, or I will have to convert this data into the embedding first?
Sunny: We'll have to convert this data into the embedding first. So this is called what? This is called the embedding. Now, this particular process, from data source, to data parsing, to chunking, to the embedding, okay? This is called what? This is called the data ingestion.
Sunny: This is called the data ingestion.
Sunny: So this is what, guys, this is the complete rack pipeline. You can take a picture of it, this is the complete rack pipeline, right?
Sunny: So is it getting clear to all of you? Tell me yes or no. Is this part clear?
Sunny: We'll discuss the data parser, you will get it.
Sunny: This idea will be more clear.
Sunny: So this is what, guys, this is the RAG pipeline.
Sunny: So, how's the session so far? Did you understand everything about the RAG pipeline? Yes or no?
Sunny: I think we're finding this session, like, very interesting and all, right?
Sunny: If you are going to revise it, definitely you will, understand, okay, more from here.
Sunny: Now, guys, we have to discuss a couple of more things. So here, guys, you can see, we'll discuss what are the differences between the RAG and the fine-tuning. So I capped a couple of differences over here with respect to the RAG and fine-tuning
Sunny: Then, guys, after that, guys, we'll enter into the data parsing. So, that's going to be a first component of the data, okay? So, I will show you the nature of the data, its storage format, its structure, and then these are the library for parsing the data, okay? And I'll tell you, guys, what a library we are going to be use for parsing the data.
Sunny: For parsing the document. And I will show you how to parse each and every kind of data. Audio, video is not required, okay? On top of that data, we are not going to be build a rack, but yeah, text, images, table, everything we are going to be discussed, and the different, different other document also. Got it, guys? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: The web is very simple, Rakesh. Nothing we have to do easily, we can scrap the data from the web.
Sunny: So don't worry about that, I can show you, don't worry.
Sunny: So, we'll, then, basically enter into the data parsing, and then, basically we'll discuss how to store the data inside the vector databases. So, two classes, two classes basically will, spend on the data parsing.
Sunny: Because that is the important part. I'll show you metadata and all everything, okay? And guys, I will not repeat everything again and again, because if I'm repeating, that breaks the flow. So I will say once, twice, and then, guys, I will move forward, okay?
Sunny: So, here you can see, I think the session is an interesting one. We'll discuss the RAG versus fine-tuning, and then I will…
Sunny: Basically.
Sunny: Come to the practical part, okay?
Sunny: So, let's take a break, and then we'll start
Sunny: Putting a timer, guys, okay? Putting a timer for 5
Sunny: Yeah, you can ask the thing in the doubt session, Sushant, that's a good thing.
Sunny: Just note down all the questions and then you can ask in a doubt session.
Sunny: Whether RAG is required, MCP is needed, right? See, Rahul. MCP is a… Little different thing, right?
Sunny: Basically, whatever services, the data ingestion and all, which I'm telling you now, we can use it as a MCP connector also. So, I will not… MCP is a different thing. See, the pipeline would be same.
Sunny: Inside that pipeline, basically, this particular context we can consume via MCP. So, it's not that fundamental concept, it's a way, basically, of utilizing these services, one of the connectors.
Sunny: Where I can add… where I can add the data sources to my pipeline.
Sunny: Getting my point.
Sunny: I told you, build an API, how you will create an API.
Sunny: We have several ways. Now, you will use a fast API for building the API. So that is one of the way… basically, way of building the API.
Sunny: Okay? So, in the same way, basically, we have this, services, we have this fundamental, we have the data sources, or anything, anything, right? We can convert it into the tool, and we can consume it via MCP connector. That's it. So, once you will understand that, that part will be clear.
Sunny: Got it?
Sunny: Okay, guys, putting a timer, then I will start again. Thank you, guys. Let's take a dinner
Sunny: Why it is showing, this in minus, huh?
Sunny: Okay, fine. So guys, I'll see you after 20 minutes.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so let's start, let's begin with the session. I hope everyone is there.
Sunny: Can you please give me quick confirmation so that we can start?
Sunny: Yes.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so let's begin. So, here, till here, actually, we understood about the RAG pipeline. So this part is clear. Is this slide clear or not?
Sunny: See, I've given you the both architecture, even I've drawn the architecture from my end, and the architecture is present over here. So you can revise in the both way, okay? So when you are going through with this particular, notes, you can revise in the… in a both way.
Sunny: So, now guys, let's do one thing. Let's understand the quick differences between the RAG versus fine-tuning. So here, basically I append one, very basic, differences, right, for an image, okay?
Sunny: So just by reading these points, you will be able to understand the differences between the RAG and the fine-tuning.
Sunny: So, here, guys, let's say, the first is going to be what? First is going to be the main purpose. So, main purpose, what is the main purpose, guys? So, the main purpose of the RAG is nothing. Give the model external knowledge or the context.
Sunny: So, from the external data sources, we are going to connect our LLM, okay, and then only we are going to generate the answer.
Sunny: Now, if we're talking about a fine-tuning, so here in the fine-tuning, basically, we teach the model new behavior, style, or format. So we are training the model only, we are retraining the model only, and we are teaching to the model the new behavior, style, or the format, okay?
Sunny: Now, we're talking about the rag, right? So instead of the rag, the model weights are going to be changed? No. The model weights are not going to be changed inside Veo.
Sunny: Inside the RAG, okay? If we're talking about the fine-tuning, so here we are doing the training. So, over here, the model weights are going to be changed. Now, the cost, basically, so it is a very, like, usually you will get a lower cost.
Sunny: if you are going to create a RAG, okay? So, but if you are performing the fine-tuning, if you are performing the training of the model, so there you will get usually higher cost. Now, data update, guys, so it is very easy. You just need to update the document, the data inside the vector database only.
Sunny: You just need to be… execute your data ingestion pipeline, that's it. That is, one and only requirement of the RAG pipeline.
Sunny: On the other hand, if we're talking about the fine-tuning, there, the retraining is required. So, whenever the data is coming, the new data is coming, okay, so at that time only, you will have to perform the retraining of your model to up-to-date with the current knowledge. So, is this difference clear? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: And you can even use the hybrid model also. First, you can fine-tune that model, okay? You can perform the supervised fine-tuning, preference tuning, whatever kind of fine-tuning you wanted to do, you can perform that fine-tuning, and then you can utilize that particular model inside your RAG pipeline.
Sunny: Even I can give you the more clarity. So, if you will look in the previous, pipeline.
Sunny: So, in the previous pipeline, you can see we have a LLM. This is what… this is my LLM. Tell me, yes or no.
Sunny: So this is what, guys, this is my LLM.
Sunny: Right? Now guys, this LLM could be anyone, anything, right? It can be your own LLM.
Sunny: It could be… OpenAI's LLM It could be Claude, Okay? Your LLM means what?
Sunny: The fine-tune LLM.
Sunny: Any LLM you can keep over here, there is no such a restriction.
Sunny: Okay? There is no such restriction.
Sunny: Right? So where, actually, you have to… at any cost, your company said, okay, you have to train your own model, the requirement will come from the company, from the management, that you have to host your own model, okay? After retraining, you have to host your own model. In that case, basically, you will have to perform the fine-tuning.
Sunny: But, if we just have to be get… if we're just going to be build a chatbot, if we're just going to be build a QSS stand, okay, in that case, we can simply do it via RAG itself.
Sunny: Getting my point? So, any QA system, any chatbot system, okay, any generation system.
Sunny: For that, basically the RAG pipeline is enough until unless company specifically is not telling you, OK, now we have to host our own model and at every places, whether it's a RAG pipeline or for the simple AI assistant also we are going to be use our own fine tune LLM, OK, until unless company is not saying, OK, now let's retain our own model. You don't need to train your own model.
Sunny: For basic Q&A, for any sort of a generational system, for any sort of a conversational AI, for any kind of chatbot system, the RAG system is enough. Making sense or not? Tell me.
Sunny: Great. So, I hope, guys, this part is clear. So, whatever theoretical point I have explained you so far, I hope that is clear. Now, I told you guys, whenever we are going to be start with the RAG, okay, so tell me, guys, what is the first component of the RAG?
Sunny: Just by looking into this architecture, what you can, understand, can you please write in the chat? Just by looking into this architecture, what you are able to understand?
Sunny: So, here, guys, the data ingestion, or the data parsing is required. So, we are going to be start this RAG, okay?
Sunny: Let me write over here. So, the first thing, we'll focus over the data ingestion.
Sunny: Right? So where we'll focus, guys, tell me. So first, we'll focus over the… Data.
Sunny: Injection.
Sunny: We'll understand about the data parsing.
Sunny: Okay? We'll understand about the vector databases.
Sunny: So, today and tomorrow, guys, tomorrow, even tomorrow.
Sunny: Today and tomorrow, okay? We'll discuss onto this, data parsing, and then next class, next weekend, guys, we'll completely focus on the vector database.
Sunny: Next Saturday and Sunday, we'll completely focus over the vector database, and then we'll come to the retrieval side. So is this part clear or not? Tell me. So just by looking into this particular architecture, you can see we are… the first priority is the data ingestion, right?
Sunny: Is RAC can follow the transfer or what kind of cushion it is, Amit Gupta,
Sunny: Is RAG follow transformer RQ? Sir, here we are using LLM, this LLM, no?
Sunny: Understand, RAG is not a LLM. RAG is not a model. RAG is a pipeline, Sargi. Pipeline.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: There are the different, different components are there, like data parsing, data, vector database, where we do the ingestion of the data, then retrieval of the data. LLM is one of the components, and that LLM has been created using the transformer architecture only.
Sunny: So your question, your ask is completely wrong.
Sunny: RAG is not a model. RAG is not a model. RAG is not a LLM. It's a complete system.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: Great. So guys, I hope this part is clear. Now, let's do one thing.
Sunny: So, we did not say… did we even perform the RAG, at least one practical of the RAG? So, how I can tell you the cost of that, huh, Deepak?
Sunny: First, let's… let me perform some practical, then only you will get some idea, okay, where your cost might go.
Sunny: Model, like, framework you're going to be used
Sunny: Which is the paid one, which is not a paid one. Then only we can estimate, no? Something, correct?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Here, OCR is a part of the data parsing only. From the, like, the scanned images, we can retrieve the data.
Sunny: Okay? How embedding LLM will generate context embedding? We'll understand that. As we'll come to that particular part, everything is going to be clear.
Sunny: Got it?
Sunny: No.
Sunny: Guys, let's do one thing. Let's, deep dive into the data, okay? Data passing. So guys, I hope this, particular image is clear. Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: Is this clear or not?
Sunny: Yes? Okay. So, guys, whenever we're talking about the data, right? So, this tags, images, audio, and the video, actually, it is called the nature of the data, or it is called the data modality.
Sunny: Right? So it is called the data modality. Tags would be there, the images would be there.
Sunny: The data could be in the form of audios, the data could be formed in the videos. But whenever we talk about the RAG or the RAG pipeline, we generally build on the text and the images pipeline.
Sunny: Okay? Sorry, we generally build on the text and the images data, okay? On this modality, actually. I think I already discussed this modality in my previous classes, correct? Now, where we are going to be store the data? So, this data, actually, we can store in any file.
Sunny: Right? So this is the file format, storage format. We can keep the data in the PDF, we can keep the data in the document, docx, okay, document, sorry, in the Word document, in the CSV file, in the JSONL file, in the YAML file, in the HTML, okay, MP3, MP4, so this is what, this is my storage format.
Sunny: In this particular format, basically, we can store the data. Now, this is the data structure, okay, how we can arrange the data. This is what is the arrangement of the data.
Sunny: This is what guys tell me. This is the arrangement of the data.
Sunny: Okay? This is what guys tell me, this is the arrangement of the data. So we can, arrange the data in the table.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: And the table could be available anywhere.
Sunny: The table can be available in the PDF, in the docx, or the table can be available in the form of CSV or in the form of Excel file. CSV is one of the way to arrange the data. SQL database is one of the way to arrange the data.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: If we are talking about the semi-structured format, then JSON, YAML, HTML, this is a semi-structured format for arranging your data.
Sunny: Right? For the arrangement of the data. Unstructured format, PDF, images, audio, video. So these are what, guys, these are the unstructured. Images, audio, and video. Mainly this one is the unstructured one.
Sunny: Getting my point. So this is the arrangement of the data, how we are going to be arranged the data. So if this image is clear, I can, definitely proceed further. Tell me, guys, tell me yes or no.
Sunny: It is clear, right?
Sunny: Even I can, write over here, so that you will get a clear understanding. So let's say, what I have, guys, let's say I have some text.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: The text is something like this, the text is… I can write one sentence.
Sunny: Maya?
Sunny: Name?
Sunny: is… Sunny, okay?
Sunny: This is what guys tell me, this is the text data.
Sunny: No.
Sunny: I can have all images also, let's say this is my image.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So this is what, this is my image, guys, right?
Sunny: Let me draw something over here, let's say this is my image.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Here I can write image.
Sunny: Now, this is what… this is a text modality.
Sunny: And this is what is the image modality.
Sunny: The nature of the data.
Sunny: Now this text or images, can I keep in the PDF? Let's say here is my PDF.
Sunny: In the PDF, I kept the text and images.
Sunny: So this is what this is about?
Sunny: File format.
Sunny: Or data format.
Sunny: I can write over here the file format.
Sunny: Or the data form.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Yes or no? Is it clear, guys? Tell me, yes
Sunny: No, even I can arrange my data in the table also. Okay, let's say I have a table.
Sunny: I had one table.
Sunny: Inside the table, I arrange the data.
Sunny: This is my table.
Sunny: Okay, that's stable.
Sunny: Let's say this table is available in the PTF.
Sunny: Table can also be available in the PDF, no?
Sunny: Tell me yes or no. So table is a way of structuring our data.
Sunny: Right? Table is a way of structuring our data. Now, we have other file data format, or let's say CSV format.
Sunny: Comma separated format. TSV format. Tab separated format.
Sunny: Let's say XLX.
Sunny: Excel format.
Sunny: So here also, we are going to be store our data in the form of tables.
Sunny: This is the data format, the file format, basically.
Sunny: Thank you.
Sunny: Let's say this is my data.
Sunny: Now, inside this column, I can arrange anything. Let's say this column is for images, this column is for text. Now, this is… this column, basically, for the numerical or categorical data. I can arrange any kind of data.
Sunny: Okay? We can structure our data over here.
Sunny: Understood, guys, yes or no? Tell me. So whenever we are going to be load the data from here.
Sunny: Again, we are going to be load in a tabular format.
Sunny: So, this is the file format. Here, basically, we are going to arrange the data.
Sunny: Okay? And then from this particular, arrangement, we are going to be load the data. Let's say we are going to be loading the tabular format. Or we could have a table directly. Let's say this is my table.
Sunny: And this particular table is append inside the PDF.
Sunny: Now, this could be available inside the docx.
Sunny: Okay? Now, to fetch the raw data from there, to fetch the raw data, this is my raw data, text.
Sunny: Images.
Sunny: Mainly the modality.
Sunny: We have to understand about what data parsing.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: We have to understand what, guys, we have to understand about the data parsing. Now, see, this data actually, whatever data we are talking about here, this data could be available, this data could be available where this data could be available on the web.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: Now, how the data is arranged over the web? Can anyone tell me?
Sunny: How the data is arranged over the web.
Sunny: It's available in the HTML one.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: So the HTML, basically, we can append the image.
Sunny: We can append the table.
Sunny: We can append the text.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: So, this is my data format.
Sunny: A file format.
Sunny: The raw data would be… the raw data would be what? Images, table, and all. Sorry, images, text, and all.
Sunny: Right? I hope this entire thing is clear. Now, if you wanted to get the data, if you wanted to get the data, so we have a several framework.
Sunny: We are not going to be learning every framework, guys, that is not at all required.
Sunny: But yeah, if we know at least a couple of frameworks, I think that would be great for us. So here you can see we have a couple of frameworks. I written a name.
Sunny: One is called the Llama Parser, okay?
Sunny: Second, it's called the DocLink, Google Document AI from the Google, Amazon Tesseract from the Amazon, Python DocX, BuyMuPDF, PDFPlumber, ParseIO, UnstructureIO, Azure Document Intelligence. So, these are some
Sunny: Framework.
Sunny: Or you can say, library.
Sunny: These are some framework, library for what, for extracting our data.
Sunny: Using this one, basically, what we can do, we can extract the data.
Sunny: Getting my point, guys, yes or no? Tell me.
Sunny: So I'll show you.
Sunny: what I'll show you guys, I can discuss onto this doc link. I can show you the practical with this doc link, even the llama parts are also okay, I can show you. DocX, PyMu, PDF, PDF Plumber, automatically being used in the backend, in, LangChain and all, I'll come to that, I'll
Sunny: uninstructured.io, again, I can utilize this also. This is also an open-source framework, and again, it is available inside the LangChain ecosystem. We can utilize that. But guys, if you wanted to use this Azure Document Search, ADI, in most of the enterprise applications, we are using it
Sunny: So for that, we should have a paid account.
Sunny: And believe me, guys, it is very expensive. I have used it personally.
Sunny: It's expensive, so we are not going to be use it inside our practical, because everyone is not having this particular, ADI and all. The same thing we can do with the Llama parser over the dockling itself, okay? Same kind of thing.
Sunny: So, Azure Document Intelligence, we are not going to be used. Unstructured.io, till some point, it will work like ADI only.
Sunny: Okay? So… we will not be using that. Even the Tesseract also, it is a paid one.
Sunny: Even the document… Google Document AI is a paid one.
Sunny: Okay. So we are not going to be use a paid tool, so we are going to be use a free one, free tool, like the doc link.
Sunny: Okay? Like, the Llama Parser. We have the other one, like, the HonestStructure.io. Okay, these are the free ones.
Sunny: Python Docx, PyMuPDF, PDFPlumber, this is also a free one, okay? Free tool. So we're going to be use that. Got it, guys? Yes or
Sunny: Is it getting clear?
Sunny: Tell me, is this part getting clear?
Sunny: So guys, I hope the RAG pipeline is getting clear to all of you.
Sunny: And, what is the first component of the RAG pipeline? If someone is going to ask you that, what do you would say?
Sunny: you would say the data parsing, okay? So first, basically, we'll focus with the data parsing, over the data parsing.
Sunny: So let's do some data parsing, let's perform some data parsing, okay? And then the next class, next week, basically, we'll discuss onto the vector databases. We'll discuss onto that, okay?
Sunny: So, here, guys, I can write. So, the first component of the RAG, basically, is going to be what?
Sunny: the data parsing.
Sunny: So we're talking about the data parsing, guys.
Sunny: So, data parsing means nothing.
Sunny: To fetch our data.
Sunny: Okay, thank you.
Sunny: To fetch the data.
Sunny: To store the data.
Sunny: Sorry, to fetch the data.
Sunny: To arrange the data.
Sunny: So that it can be pro… it can be, basically provide to the next… next stage, to the next component. Either directly I can provide it to the LLM, or direct… I can keep the data inside some databases, middleware, right?
Sunny: So that is the main aim of the data parsing. Now, what all tools and, technology I'm going to be used for the data parsing? I can show you with a doc link. It's a very good open source library, it can do everything.
Sunny: unstructured.io, again, basically, I can show you, or if I will not show you, then, from your end also, you can explore. Okay? But, whatever thing we are going to do via unstructured.io, the same thing we can do with the dockling also.
Sunny: Sorry?
Sunny: Then, guys, we have the other, framework, like Llama Parser. I can show you the Llama Parser. So, Dockling and Llama Parser, two… wire 2-1,
Sunny: Llama parts are okay.
Sunny: This we'll discuss. unstructured.io and the parser.io I can skip, because it is doing the same kind of work. Whatever work, basically, we will be able to do via dockling in the Llama parser, we can do using the unstructured.io and the parser.io also. Okay?
Sunny: So this thing will do. Now some framework guys, it is like automatically one we would be using somewhere. So we're talking about the Pymu PDF, a very important, very good library for dealing with a PDF, PDF lumber. Okay.
Sunny: in industry, directly or indirectly, are going to be used this library, PyMuPDF and the PDF Plumber. Python docx, again.
Sunny: It's one of the good library for extracting the data from the documents, okay? So this library is for the PDF.
Sunny: This is, again, for the PDF.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: This library for the docx.
Sunny: This DocLink Llama parser, basically, it's for the OCR kind of stuff, for the… from the scan image, for the PDF, for the DOCX.
Sunny: For the PPTs.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: OCR means what? Scanned image.
Sunny: Even for what? For the layout parsing.
Sunny: Right? For the, scanned image, layout parsing, for arranging the metadata.
Sunny: For arranging the tables, okay, for fetching the data from the tables and for arranging that, right?
Sunny: So, guys, this is the important one, getting my point. So, we are not going to be used on a structure.io, parser.io, because every library is not required, I just written the name.
Sunny: DocLink and the Llama parser is enough, okay? And this particular library, automatically, we are going to be used for the PDF and for the DocX, okay? If we are going to be using the LangChain wrapper, then indirectly, it is using this library only in the bac
Sunny: Then guys, the other one which we are using in the industry because industry sometime don't use the open source one. So we are going so they are basically we'll find out the EDI Azure Document Intelligence. Then some is from the Amazon, some and from the GCP right.
Sunny: So these are the paid one, guys.
Sunny: If you wanted to explore it from your end, you can do. But again, the same kind of work, it can be done by the dockling and the llama parser, I have seen.
Sunny: at some places and some enterprises, some industry, people are using this library as an alternative, because it is a very cost one. It is a… it will give you very, like, a very, good bill, right? So, the costing of this ADI and all is very high.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So costing of this Adi and all is very high. I have used it in most of the application. But the same kind of work. Basically, we can do via dockling and the llama parts are also okay. So we are not going to be. Use this library in our application, because everyone is not having this account. I will be focusing on the dockling and the llama pass. Got it, guys, tell me yes or no. Is this part getting clear to all of you?
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Not cost-effective, it's an expensive one. It's not a cost-effective.
Sunny: It's an expensive one.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: expensive one.
Sunny: Is it getting clear? If it is getting clear, please let me know, so that we can proceed.
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Okay, now guys, one more thing, what we can do.
Sunny: So, here, guys…
Sunny: Oh, one more thing I would like to explain. See, we are talking about the Lang chain.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, we were talking about what, guys, tell me? We were talking about the LANG chain, okay? Now, we're talking about the LANG chain, guys. Now, tell me, what is the LA
Sunny: What do you understand, what do you think with the LangC
Sunny: Tell me, guys, what do you understand, what do you think with the LangChain? So, LangChain is a frame
Sunny: LinkedIn is what? It is a… framework.
Sunny: Now, this LangChain, actually, it is providing you everything. Everything means what?
Sunny: It's providing you the document.
Sunny: Loader.
Sunny: It's providing the document parser.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: It's providing the method for the chunking.
Sunny: Okay. It's providing you the access of the… Vector databases.
Sunny: The different, different vector databases.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: It's providing you access of what? It's providing the access of the different, different databases, the vector databases, okay?
Sunny: Now, guys, this… This, basically, LangChain is providing the integration with the different, different models.
Sunny: What are different, different LLMs?
Sunny: With a different, different API.
Sunny: This LangChain is providing the integration with a different, different cloud.
Sunny: It's providing the method for the memory management.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: It's providing the method for what? It's providing the method for what?
Sunny: Providing the method of for the.
Sunny: Memory.
Sunny: management.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: No, guys, this… Langchen, actually.
Sunny: It is providing you the access of what, guys, tell me.
Sunny: For the chaining and all, right, you can chain the multiple component.
Sunny: LCEL.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, LangChain is providing you the… LangChain is a framework which is providing you the all sort of a…
Sunny: all sorts of services which is required for building one AI application.
Sunny: AI application means what? The application which is built around the large language model.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, one more thing, guys, if we're talking about the model, API, LLM, So, Langchain…
Sunny: is having their own model, or LangChain is just a wrapper.
Sunny: Which is providing you the access from the different, different API. What do you think, guys? Tell me.
Sunny: Langchen is a rapper.
Sunny: Right? With that, you can access the model from the OpenAI
Sunny: You can access the model from the cloud.
Sunny: Okay? You can access the model from the Jimny… From the hugging phase, From the Olama.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: Similar to that, LangChain is provide you the parser.
Sunny: Or it is just a wrapper on top of the other library? Tell me, guys.
Sunny: It is just a wrapper, guys. LangChain is not having its own parser.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Lang chain.
Sunny: is… not… Having… It's… own parts, sir.
Sunny: It is providing you the wrapper on top of the different, different library, like what?
Sunny: Like… PDF Plumber.
Sunny: Like… PyMuPDF.
Sunny: Like… Python docx.
Sunny: Like, guys?
Sunny: And structure IO.
Sunny: And several other.
Sunny: So, these are the actual packages.
Sunny: Python, sorry, these are the actual library, these one.
Sunny: And Langchain is just a wrapper, actually. Langchain is what, guys? Langchain is just a wrapper.
Sunny: Making sense to all of you, tell me yes or no. Tell me, tell me guys, fast, I'm just waiting
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, here, I have already written, if you're going to be read it out.
Sunny: If you're going to be read it out, guys, this
Sunny: LangChain does not provide the document loader. LangChain does provide the document loader, but in most cases, LangChain is not doing the low-level parsing by itself. It merely provides a common wrapper interface over different parsing libraries and services.
Sunny: LangChain itself is not primarily a parsing library, okay? LangChain provides document loader, but many of those loaders internally use the existing parsing library, such as PyMuPDF, PyPDF, PDFPlumber.
Sunny: Python docx, unstructured doclink, and the other one. So, LangChain acts like a wrapper or integration layer that gives us the common document format.
Sunny: Okay, this makes it easy to plug past documents into the RAG pipeline.
Sunny: Is this part clear to all of you? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: Tell me. So, we're talking about the LangChain, guys. Via LangChain, even you can access
Sunny: The ADI, Azure Document Intelligence, You can access the Google Document AI.
Sunny: You can access the AWS Amazon Tesseract.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: That's right.
Sunny: So, you can basically access anything via LangChain.
Sunny: You can access anything via LangChain, guys. So LangChain, actually… LangChain, actually, it is not a data parsing tool. LangChain is a framework which is providing you the plug-and-play button from every other framework or from every other library.
Sunny: Your understanding is clear or not, tell me, yes or no?
Sunny: If your understanding is clear, you can let me know. Sadiq is saying no, I think everyone is saying yes.
Sunny: Only this person is saying no.
Sunny: What is your doubt, Sadiq? You can discuss with me in the doubt session, if you have any sort of a doubt, okay? We can… I can explain you. But you will have to wait a few more… you will have to basically wait for a few more classes, if your fundamental and understanding is not clear.
Sunny: So until unless we are not going to be basically explaining the practical side, maybe you will be confused. So once I'll explain a couple of practical, then the idea will be more clear. Same thing goes to the Swetha also. Got it, Swetha? Everything will be clear in the going forward classes.
Sunny: Got it.
Sunny: So, fine guys, I hope this… you like this theoretical session about the RAG and the other thing and all. So, just give me the final confirmation so that I can proceed with some practical, okay? I can show you some data.
Sunny: parsing one, and then, in tomorrow's session, I'll discuss in a very detail about the data parsing and all. I will, explain you the, the each and everything of the data parsing, guys. There are so many things that are data parsing. See, let me tell you, what all things are there, basically, which we can discuss.
Sunny: So, arrangement of the data we can discuss, okay? I can show you, basically, how to fetch the data
Sunny: how to arrange the data inside the .AMD file, how to arrange the data inside the .JSON file, okay?
Sunny: So these are very important file, guys, whenever we are working in the industry. So we always, keep our data into some intermediate file that is an AMD or JSON, so that going forward, we can utilize that, right?
Sunny: So, I'll show you, basically, how you can do the arrangement of the data. So, let's say we have an image data, how to keep it there. If we have a text data, how to keep it there
Sunny: How to handle the metadata? How to handle the layout?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: images, tags, metadata, layout, okay? And everything, guys, the document object and all, everything we are going to be discussed, okay?
Sunny: What is the purpose of the parsing? Parsing, see, we have parsed the data. Now, that particular information we'll be giving to the LLM, okay? So, after 3 to 4 classes on Ansingji, that part will be clear, once we'll develop the entire pipeline of the RAG. Got it?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So guys, I'm, taking one minute of break, quick water break, then, basically will.
Sunny: Start with the practical, okay?
Sunny: So let me… and guys, now tell me one thing.
Sunny: So, for this type of practical, do we require the Google Colab means GPU?
Sunny: Or we can do in a local only.
Sunny: We can do in our local only, okay?
Sunny: CPU picker sakte hai. GPU is not required for this one.
Sunny: Why? Tell me.
Sunny: Because here, we are not doing the… Training.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: RAG means… RAG means what, guys? RAG does not mean training.
Sunny: Okay? We are not doing a training. That's it of the… that's it. So, every sort of a practical we can do in a local itself, over our CPU. I'm not denying that I cannot do the Google Colab, I can do, but there the GPU will not be required.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, fine, let me do one thing, guys, let me open the notebook. Guys, taking one minute of break, and then I'll perform the practical, okay? Give me one minute.
Sunny: Okay, guys, can we start again? I hope everyone is there.
Sunny: What's the fifth point? Fifth point, I think it's a memory. Cloud. This is the cloud, okay? So, the cloud integration is also there.
Sunny: So, let's do one thing, let me create a file, just a second.
Sunny: I'm going to open my same folder. This is the folder.
Sunny: Let me open it inside the VS Code first.
Sunny: Yep.
Sunny: code dot.
Sunny: Okay, so… here is my complete, practical and all everything.
Sunny: Let me update it.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so here is the folder, the RAG introduction, you will get the entire practical over here itself.
Sunny: So, I'll share the code, don't worry, I'll share after the session. Now, inside this one, I have one file, let me…
Sunny: remove this file from here. I will share the fresh note… fresh file, okay?
Sunny: So this is the older file, let me remove it from here.
Sunny: So, just a second.
Sunny: Okay, so I'm going to be close all this file first.
Sunny: This is the handwritten notes. I will again keep the…
Sunny: fresh notes, because it's an older one. I'll, basically keep the fresh, okay?
Sunny: So, now, guys, what I'm doing, see…
Sunny: First of all, I have to install the LangChain-related, libraries.
Sunny: So, let me create one file.
Sunny: My file name is what?
Sunny: data.
Sunny: Part C.
Sunny: Data.
Sunny: Part 1.
Sunny: LinkedIn.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: dot IPYNB. So, this is my file.
Sunny: data parsing, part 1 line chain. Now, here, basically, I'll write one print statement, so print all, okay.
Sunny: I'm just checking whether I'm able to run it or not
Sunny: So I'll select my environment first.
Sunny: Okay, so this is my environment, environment 3.12, and even I have an environment with a 3.11 also. Anyone I can use, so yeah, it is working fine.
Sunny: Let me increase… The appearance.
Sunny: So I hope it is clearly visible.
Sunny: Let me delete this file also.
Sunny: I'll provide you the fresh notes, okay, don't worry
Sunny: So, yeah, this is set now.
Sunny: Now, guys, I will open my requirement.txt, so… let me check whether this is working or not… okay. So, I will open my requirement.txt, and here, basically, I'll, keep the important packages.
Sunny: The first package is going to be LangChain Community, so it is not there, I'll keep it over here
Sunny: LangChain and the LangChain community, two packages required, so let me keep it LangChain and the LangChain community, okay?
Sunny: So, let me keep these two packages.
Sunny: Now, guys, what I'll do, I'll keep some other packages also, as I told you. LangChain is not having any parser, it is using the different other library for that.
Sunny: So, here, guys, what I'm doing, I'm going to be keep the different, different packages. So, first is the PyPDF for handling the
Sunny: Second is a Python docx for handling the docx. Pandas, okay, OpenXL for handling the Excel file-related file, or CSV-related file, then Beautiful, SOAP for doing the data parsing and all. So these particular packages will be required to us.
Sunny: Okay? If I wanted to do the data parsing using the LangChain.
Sunny: Okay, and LangChain is using this particular library in the backend for, fetching the data, right? Now, what I'll do, guys, I will quickly, install the requirement.txt, so what I can do, I can change my environment over here.
Sunny: Select another kernel, Python environment, and then I can utilize this ENV, okay?
Sunny: Now guys, here, basically what I'm doing, I'm going to be install the library, so pip install hyphen r.
Sunny: requirement.txt.
Sunny: So once I learn it, guys, so I will be able to install all the mentioned packages.
Sunny: So let it install, and don't worry, guys, I'll give you the code base so that you can run it.
Sunny: So we're installing all the library… all the packages inside the environment folder.
Sunny: We'll wait for a few minutes, then I will write the code, okay?
Sunny: I hope everyone is getting everything.
Sunny: If…
Sunny: I will end the class within 10 minutes, Sumit, don't worry.
Sunny: Recon.txt is here, Anuj Gupta, see, this is the Recon.txt.
Sunny: I'll share the requirement.txt, don't worry.
Sunny: Also, saying UBSync, uBSync is required when I'm maintaining the file, okay? The TOML file and the other Ubilitate file. But as of now, I'm not doing that, Aditi, so that command is not required to me.
Sunny: It's a UV method only, Rena, so I hope it is clear.
Sunny: We can use 3.12 also, that is not, like, I'm not denying with that, Satish, you can utilize 3.12 also.
Sunny: Any Python version, than this 3.10, okay, more than 3.10, you can utilize.
Sunny: Your application will work fine, even with 3.11 and 3.12 also.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: It's taking some time, because these packages are the big one.
Sunny: new PDF, docx, pandas, open Excel, okay? It takes time.
Sunny: Oh.
Sunny: This required library, actually, it comes from the requirement Rajesh, okay?
Sunny: It's not like that I'm, like, just waking up and, thinking, okay, not today which library I need to install inside my environment. Okay?
Sunny: So, it comes from the requirement. Let's say today I have to parse out PDF.
Sunny: So you will search, okay, which library is good for the PDF, which library I have to use.
Sunny: you came up, okay, PyPTF is a library, PyPTF Plumber is a library, then you will mention that particular require… inside the require.txt, and you will install it.
Sunny: Got it?
Sunny: So, this requirement.txt, actually, it always come from where? It always come from the…
Sunny: It always comes from a requirement, got it?
Sunny: From our use cases, from our problem statement.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: Now, let's do one thing, let's perform some practical
Sunny: So, first of all, I'm going to be import couple of, packages. So, these are some packages, guys, which I have.
Sunny: Which I kept, basically, in the other file, see?
Sunny: Langchain is having this text loader, PyPDF loader, CSV loader, doc2text loader, unstructured HTML loader, and the JSON loader. So every kind of loader basically will get where inside the… You will get where, guys? You will get inside the LangChain.
Sunny: Getting my point, yes or no?
Sunny: So what we can do, guys, then we can, basically keep the document, okay? We can keep the, different, different files, whether it's a TXT file, PDF file, CSV file, DOCX file.
Sunny: Or we can keep the HTML file, or any sort of a JSON file, we'll be able to read the data directly from that file, okay?
Sunny: So, where is those files? I think I capped in one of the folder. Just a second, let me check it out.
Sunny: Where I capped those files.
Sunny: Yes, we'll deploy the pipeline. We'll, in the project, basically, we'll do that.
Sunny: So for that, basically, we'll have to do some incremental loading of the data, right? So we can write some cron job, airflow jobs and all, and we'll be able to do that. That's not a very typical thing
Sunny: It's a day-to-day job of the data engineers and all, and then they can do that chunking, embedding, and then they can keep the data inside the… any sort of a repository or directory, or in any sort of a data lake, okay, data storage.
Sunny: We can directly build it over the AWS also. We have several services over there, the Lambda step function and all. We can directly build over there, okay?
Sunny: Guys, where is that folder I kept? So, let's do one thing, guys, what you say. Can we do it tomorrow, the entire practical of the data parsing?
Sunny: Because I think data folder seems incomplete.
Sunny: If you all agree, then I can do it tomorrow, because right now it's 10.30.
Sunny: Oh, okay.
Sunny: So… I can show you the complete practical, whatever I told, okay?
Sunny: Today you can revise the theory and all, so today I am, leaving a little bit early, or 10 to 15 minutes earlier.
Sunny: And I think we took 20-minute break, then I started 10 minutes late, so just a 2-hour session today. No worries, sometime happens. So tomorrow, what we'll do, guys, you know? We'll do this entire practical, okay? I'll show you the entire practical with the data parsing. So I'm having two parts of the data parsing.
Sunny: One is a basic one and the second is an advanced one. Okay.
Sunny: So, let me create one more file over here, the data parsing 2. So, in the advanced data parsing, I'll show you the table parsing and all everything, how you can parse the table and all.
Sunny: And then, we'll understand about the databases. So, data… Passed to IEP Y&B.
Sunny: So, advanced parsing also I'll discuss in the upcoming classes. Now, one more thing, guys. I can provide you this note so that you can go through with it, and you can…
Sunny: Basically revise all the theoretical stuff.
Sunny: Got it?
Sunny: So, class 29… handwritten notes… Jito for July.
Sunny: 2026 RAG introduction, okay?
Sunny: So, this is the handwritten notes.
Sunny: Guys, I'm providing you all the files and all everything, just a second.
Sunny: Even the requirement.txt will also be there.
Sunny: And guys, tomorrow we have to be installed some other advanced packages, okay, dockling and all, so that I will discuss.
Sunny: Commenting the code, and then syncing it to the GitHub.
Sunny: We can, basically do some, POC kind of experiment, okay?
Sunny: We can build some POCs and all to check out which parser is working good. Some experiment will have to be performed. Got it, Sohil?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, we can complete the whole syllabus and all, so don't worry about the syllabus and all, guys, okay? See, this thing is the very important one. You need to be focused
Sunny: Okay, because this is not going to be fade for next 3 to 5 year.
Sunny: Right? So don't, like, say, sir, okay, so you completed syllabus one month late or two months late, because that's just a matter of two to three year, next two to three year. So please focus, please understand that this fundamental, this Agentic AI, RAG, generative AI is very important for your career, guys.
Sunny: Okay? So don't do that negotiation for one month or two months. Even though if you are going to be completed, like, one month or two months late, that is also fine. But the understanding of the concept is also very important. You won't believe, guys, I released one course three years back.
Sunny: The generative AI codes. Okay, I taught over there. Still, people are learning from those videos, because that is still relevant.
Sunny: Getting my point.
Sunny: So, this fundamental, Agentic AI, Generative AI, this application, cloud, RAG, data parsing, it's a very important one.
Sunny: Got it? So we have to focus onto that side. How we… basically, you can leverage as much as… as much as knowledge from this course. Not, like, just to follow the timeline and all, okay? So this is my promise. We'll be completing everything in a timeline.
Sunny: Okay, one month could be here and there, one or two months, but yeah, we are going to be complete everything within a timeline itself. Got it?
Sunny: Yep.
Sunny: Okay, so I've given you all the notes and all everything, you can directly take it from the GitHub itself, so just check out the GitHub. Let me open that.
Sunny: Yeah, that's what I'm saying, guys. What will happen? Tell me. Right? But guys, the knowledge which you are acquiring from here, from this session, it's very important.
Sunny: I'm talking about the fresher, actually. Okay, mainly the fresher, and whoever is the fresher inside the generative AI.
Sunny: With all the, like, IT experience.
Sunny: Got it?
Sunny: Yep.
Sunny: So, just take all the notes and all from here, and guys, the rest of the thing we'll do in the next class, right? So, if you don't have any doubt, you can drop the session. And guys, please focus on this assignment, this is very important.
Sunny: If you're going to do this assignment now, see, your entire doubt and all everything will be clear related to the fine-tuning. So spend some time onto this assignment, and please do it. Next weekend, we are having the demonstration of it, okay?
Sunny: Yeah.
Sunny: So fine, guys, if you don't have any doubt, you can drop the session. I'll see you again in the next class, that is tomorrow. And 3R is straightforward, 3R we are going to focus on the data parsing only. So that's going to be a practical session completely, okay?
Sunny: Thank you guys, bye, take care. After 2 minutes, I will start the doubt session.
Sunny: So let me put the timer for the 2 minutes, and then I'll start. Thank you guys, thank you very much.
Sunny: Yeah, bye.
Sunny: Yeah, so guys, let's start the doubt session. Yes, Shukla, what's your doubt
Sunny: Yes, please go ahead with your doubt.
Sunny: Just a second, yes, let me…
Sunny: Yeah, yes, can you please speak again?
Yash Shukla: Hello, sir, am I audible now?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, you are audible.
Yash Shukla: Sir, regarding the assignment which you gave, so, one thing I have to ask that, if I can show you… I have completed the assignment till SFP. See, the reason I have completed till that, because regarding DPO, I have to ask. So, when we will load the DPO adapter, when we will preference tune it, so…
Yash Shukla: I have… I was reading through ChatGPT, then I found out two approaches. Either we can load base model, then on top of it, SFT, and then top of it, we will train the BPO.
Yash Shukla: And the approach was, we can directly take the model from base model, and then we can go for DPO. So, what do you think will be a better approach? Because I think training with SFT is…
Yash Shukla: Likely to give better results.
Sunny: So, that's what is the assignment, right? Yes, so you will have to figure it out, that.
Sunny: What is the correct approach? Okay. See, if I'm saying SF… if I'm saying, okay, do the one thing, do the, like, loading of the model on top of the base model. So, how you will blindly trust on that until you don't have some result onto it, right? So that's what… that's why I've given the assignment. Just do that experiment.
Sunny: Do some evaluation, okay, do in a both way, understand the process, and then make a conclusion, got it?
Yash Shukla: Okay, sir. And sir, one more thing, I was also trying to, integrate the front-end backend regarding to the project, because when I read about the project, it was… it is a really good product, so I can implement, it like a full-fledged web app only through this. But the problem which I'm facing is, I'm…
Yash Shukla: I have done a safety training, and I'm, getting the result. Means I'm getting, I've got the data set of 26,000, somewhat, of IT helpless. So I've trained only the subset of it, like, the 600 samples. So I even got the formula also, like, there is one formula as it is.
Yash Shukla: 600 into 2 upon 8, like it is, for example, the batch size is 2, the 4 is the gradient accumulation, and then 2 is the effort.
Yash Shukla: So I also got to know in the process that, what is this, formula and how we are coming to a number like 150. So I also found out this thing.
Yash Shukla: So, the experiment is good, but what I have to ask is, I'm using Qwen 1.5 billion model to SF… for SFT and DPO. It is working, but at the same time, when I'm using it for inferencing, like, to give,
Yash Shukla: it to give answers from it on my web app, but then it is saying that you are not, allowed to access it because it is paid. So, can you tell what is this difference? I'm able to use it, but I'm not able to inference through it. I'm not able to use its inference API.
Yash Shukla: So, what is this thing, sir?
Sunny: Inference API after… Uploading the model, is it?
Yash Shukla: You should know the controller list.
Sunny: You train the model, okay?
Yash Shukla: Yes, s.
Sunny: But when you use it in a web app for the inferencing, you're cutting the error. That's the main thing.
Yash Shukla: Then I have to use, sir, for that purpose, for I have to use any of the free models. So, the four options which you gave me, like, it was Gemma, Llama, and, Quen.
Yash Shukla: So, all the 3s, they were not free. So, I have to use one model named as LiquidLFM, which is free for inferencing. It gives inference API for free. So, I have to use it, if I have to just, you know, broadcast my result or broadcast the chat like ChatGPT does.
Yash Shukla: To the user. So I don't know what is this difference, because I'm able to use for SFT training and for DPU training the phone model.
Sunny: Exact error case or exact quota error.
Yash Shukla: Sir, exactly, I don't know if you can, I don't know if you can see that token, right? I don't know if you can read or write anything, right? So, I don't know if you can see it, but I have to add the payment method, and I have to pay for it.
Yash Shukla: Oh, dearly.
Sunny: Gateway error, show me the error, okay? What is the exact error? Show me that, okay.
Yash Shukla: Sir, I can, share if you can…
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, you can share the.
Yash Shukla: Person.
Sunny: Yeah, Raghu, what's your doubt.
Yash Shukla: So, sir, now is my screen visible?
Sunny: No, share the screen. Share the screen first.
Sunny: Let me take this, then I'll come to you, Raghu, okay? Raghu, Swati, Bala, and Sunil.
Yash Shukla: Okay, so sir, first thing which I have to show you, that's…
Yash Shukla: If I can show you my code.
Yash Shukla: Sir, in this code, in the… in the train STF part. So, this is all the things which you have taught us, so I have set up everything, I've studied from ChatGPT, so everything is working fine. And I'm also getting the, you know, the…
Yash Shukla: adapter in the SFT, I've also saved it, like, if you can see, adapter.model.safetensor, and these are all things I'm
Yash Shukla: So, yeah, in this fine-tuning portion, I'm able to just use the Qwen model very easily.
Sunny: No, sir, everything I got, show me the error, final error.
Yash Shukla: Sir, as well, to… just a second, sir, I'll show you the, error.
Yash Shukla: more.
Yash Shukla: And in this…
Yash Shukla: Sounds perfect.
Yash Shukla: NSM.
Yash Shukla: Sir, I think error will not load, right now, I'm not… because I just closed the file. So, if I can show you in the next class, I will not close the file. The only thing, sir, I'm not able to… just to tell you how, ki inference API, sir, ki si model ka use maker, bana ho ki wo kaya darai ki scale up ko passa dena podega.
Yash Shukla: Yagar muja chat, jibuti kitara ki si question ka answer usko sa bilwana hai. So, bosski lekhi paisa bang.
Sunny: free model mein pase nahi lagta hai, right? Matlab wo gated model aapko maase access lane aapk.
Yash Shukla: Okay.
Sunny: Gated model aap to usme jaake aap information filkar di jawaap ko eksidi, denka gated model ke lipa
Sunny: Wait, karo, aap mir ko screenshot de dena, error ka.
Yash Shukla: You're welcome, M.
Sunny: Okay, thank you.
Yash Shukla: So thank you for that.
bala personal: Hey, Sunny. H.
raghu.pr: Bye, sir.
Sunny: Wait, wait, wait. Here, Raghu. First, you go.
raghu.pr: Hi, Jenny. I just wanted to show you something. Can I share my screen?
Sunny: Yeah, you can share.
SWATI DORGE: Can I go ahead with a quick question? I have a very quick one.
Sunny: Wait, Shrati, coming to.
SWATI DORGE: Sure.
raghu.pr: Oh.
raghu.pr: Sonny, can you see my screen?
Sunny: Yeah, you can see.
raghu.pr: What?
Sunny: Yes, it is visible.
raghu.pr: Yeah, it is… is it visible?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, it is vis.
raghu.pr: One to two months back, I was working in NA10.
raghu.pr: So, yeah, my senior used to tell me, build some chatbots using n8n.
raghu.pr: So, yeah, this is the one I built during my internship days. Like, currently I have only one or two months of experience.
raghu.pr: Right here as an intern in my startup company.
Sunny: -H.
raghu.pr: So, can you just see how is it?
raghu.pr: Like, a webhook for, you know, Chat input.
raghu.pr: Like, taking the input from, after data cleaning and all. Split out crypto is for if the new data again is coming for that.
raghu.pr: And inserting into a PC vector.
raghu.pr: And… default total… Loaders…
raghu.pr: Tokens Twitter and chunk size, chunk overlap, like, I'm not sure that half, like, is, if I did 100% correct or not, but I just wanted to show you something.
raghu.pr: These are the…
raghu.pr: workflows that I added later, but yeah, as a simple RackChat part, I just wanted to show you this one.
raghu.pr: And, on the question that I have…
Sunny: This is your final working chatbot now, right?
raghu.pr: Yes, yes, yes.
Sunny: So what this what problem does this chat bot solve?
raghu.pr: No, basically, they have told me to, you know, there is one in SP, School 360 is a web application, basically.
raghu.pr: For, cool enterprise ERP solution platforms.
raghu.pr: So, just, they wanted to have one chatbot on the website screen.
raghu.pr: So, for that scenario, I built this one. In the same way, I also built for another chat, but for a…
raghu.pr: Like… As you can see, whatever the data that we are coming… getting from the website.
raghu.pr: We are cleaning it, scraping it, and storing it.
raghu.pr: And,
raghu.pr: This is the data retrieval part, and also when, you know, any user, if you want to,
raghu.pr: You know, schedule a meeting with any salesperson, that and all he can do.
Sunny: -H.
raghu.pr: Oh yeah.
Sunny: You said something is cool 360 ERP, right? What is this?
raghu.pr: Okay, one second, I will show you.
Sunny: You are showing one screen, or just another screen also?
raghu.pr: Okay, my question is, like, I chunked the data and I stored in a PG vector database.
raghu.pr: So, as the relevant question also, it is not taking semantically, it is not able to retrieve the answer semantically.
Sunny: Mmhm.
raghu.pr: Yeah, that's my question.
raghu.pr: Like, for example, if you're asking any question related.
Sunny: So, what retrieval technique you are using?
raghu.pr: Basically, using… like, from embeddings only, basically I'm retrieving it from… retrieving from a vector store.
Sunny: Mmhm.
raghu.pr: And this embedding model is…
Sunny: We have the different retrieving technique now, and even while we are retrieving, right, so which similarities technique you are using, whether it's a cosine or any other technique.
raghu.pr: Cosine, cosine, cosine, similarity, as you were saying.
Sunny: You are retrieving the data, correct?
raghu.pr: Yes, yes.
Sunny: Using the cosine similarity on top of.
raghu.pr: Yes, yes, yes, yeah.
Sunny: how many top chunks you are retrieving, right? How we are going to be evaluated there, whether it is correct or not, with that user prompt and all. So, have you used that kind of thing in… in backend, right, while you are retrieving the data?
raghu.pr: Yeah.
Sunny: Because, see, how I can understand, basically, what, you are retrieving.
Sunny: Okay, if you can show me some results, okay, Sunny, this is my question, this is what I'm retrieving, what I want this. Now, this is my retrieving technique, can you show me how to tweak into that, what kind of technique I need to use, whether I need to use the keyword along with the, this retrieval, or I need to use any other kind of retrieval technique, okay, with some enhancement and all. Okay, the different other hundreds retrieving, strategies we have nowadays, okay, so what needs to be used over there?
Sunny: So, if you're going to be asked in that way, then I can help you over there. But if you're directly saying, Sunny, I'm getting… not getting this, then how I would like… how I would be able to understand that, actually.
raghu.pr: Yes, sure, Sonny, I get it. Like, what and other queries will be there? I just have to write it down, and I will, you know, come up.
Sunny: Oh.
raghu.pr: Sunny.
Sunny: Correct.
raghu.pr: Yes. Sure, Sunny.
Sunny: Got it. So just keep those queries with you, show me the technique. So based on that, we can do some enhancement now.
raghu.pr: Sure, Sunny.
Sunny: Yah.
raghu.pr: And even, yeah, to be honest, I also had a little tough experience, like.
Sunny: No, no, that is fine. That is fine. Okay. Just spend some more time. Don't be in a hurry. Spend 10 to more 15 days. We are into the RAG chapter now. Okay. Understand from there as well. Then come up with the correct question. That is very important. Got it?
raghu.pr: Sure, sir. Yeah.
raghu.pr: I got it.
raghu.pr: Thank you.
Sunny: Okay, Raku is done now.
Sunny: Swati, what's your question?
SWATI DORGE: Yeah, so everybody here has a project set up and a lot of libraries installed and all.
SWATI DORGE: I missed a couple of previous modules.
SWATI DORGE: Can I start directly from RAG's assignments, or do I need to…
SWATI DORGE: complete previous assignments.
SWATI DORGE: because I… theoretically, I'm clear, because I was attending other course. I have a data sciences background.
SWATI DORGE: So, theoretically, I don't.
Sunny: Do that setup and all, ma'am. I already shown in the first two classes. So do that setup and all, and be ready with that setup so that we can perform this RAC practical. Got it?
SWATI DORGE: Okay, so I have to go to the very first two sessions.
Sunny: First, just follow first four sessions, there you will get the entire setup and all. I think one session was taken by the model, so… and after that, again, I took one more session for the setup. So you can follow my session, okay? There I shown you some simpler way. I'm not saying model was,
SWATI DORGE: I don't mind, saying specific date, or the session.
Sunny: Just… that's what I'm saying, let's just check with the first four classes, got it?
SWATI DORGE: First four classes, I'll do.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah.
SWATI DORGE: Thank you. And today's session was really good. Thank you so much.
Sunny: Thank you, ma'am. Thank you. By.
SWATI DORGE: Bye.
Sunny: Yeah, Bala, please go ahead with the doubt.
bala personal: Yeah, thank you. Thank you for giving an opportunity.
bala personal: So I have three questions, Sunny, actually. So yesterday, I attended Marathon, conducted by Chris, actually. So it's very great. It was completely sat on that.
Sunny: Oh, dude.
bala personal: Yeah, so today, just, you know, when you're telling, I was just revising it to myself, oh, it's correct, everything is, so I have 3 questions here, actually, so,
Sunny: Yes.
bala personal: So, yeah, you see yesterday, right, so it's not today. Today, you've shown us, you know, how the components are placed in RAG, actually. So there is one component is, there is one box is similarity search, in the…
bala personal: in the right side box, in the whiteboard, you had two board… two boxes. One is, retrieval, one is, so ingestion, and one is retrieval, right? So in the… in the retrieval, we have, called similarity search. So that similarity search box is…
bala personal: Externally, we need to take care, or VectorDB itself is going to take care of that similar research.
Sunny: So we have to take care that every sort of a configuration, we are going to be right.
bala personal: Okay, with the land chain, we are going to use, to do this,
Sunny: We can use the LangChain, or from scratch also, we can build that. So that is completely fine, because LangChain is also what? It is just a piece of code which was written by someone, we are just going to use it, correct?
Sunny: So, either we can utilize the configured classes from the LangChain, or directly we can write it from RSL also, okay?
bala personal: Okay. So VectorDB is not going to take care of the same searching techniques, right?
Sunny: See, we are doing every technique, every searching technique in the VectorDB only, but that is on our hand.
Sunny: Okay? That lower-level configuration we can do for searching the thing. Which searching technique we are going to be use, okay? Then how many chunks we are going to be retrieved from there.
Sunny: Getting my point, which index needs to be configured, okay? How much we have to be, like, configure the scaling factor, okay, for the better output? How to do the re-ranking after getting the output?
Sunny: So that's all the configuration we can do. Got it?
bala personal: Okay.
Sunny: Mmm.
bala personal: Yeah, so…
bala personal: One more thing, one more question is that, how embedding, like, I asked in the chat, right, so, when we are doing… we have a big document, let's say, it's a two…
bala personal: Two pages document, okay? We are chunking page by page. Let's say one page, one chunk, second page.
Sunny: Mmm.
bala personal: Second check.
bala personal: So…
bala personal: LLM is a stateless, correct? It's an API model-based, means it does not remember the previous context. If you're sending a first chunk.
bala personal: It'll generate the related context embedding. If you send a second chunk, it'll forgot the first chunk results.
bala personal: Because it's, it does not show anywhere in the, API, open API, whatever, servers.
bala personal: So, in the second chunk, how it's correlated to correlate the information of first chunk to generate contextual embeddings?
Sunny: Sir, we can do the memory management in that case.
Sunny: To memorize a conversation, we can do the memory management.
Sunny: Okay, and here you are saying, let's say we have a first chunk, second chunk, okay, the thing does not work like this, sir.
Sunny: Let's say we have one question. With that particular question, if two chunk is related, then both of the chunks will be retrieved from the vector databases.
Sunny: Okay.
bala personal: embedding model, I'm trying to say, so…
bala personal: You see, it's shown in the… today, the box, how the ingestion will be done.
Sunny: I haven't saw any sort of a retrieval embedding and all. That will come into the future classes. Today was just an introduction. This is the embedding, this is the retrieval and all. That's it.
bala personal: Yeah, but chunk 1, chunk 2, chunk 3, right, sir? Chunk 1 is independent of context of another. Chunk 2 is.
Sunny: See, sir, things does not work like this. Again, understand, let's say I have one quotient. If that particular quotient, if two chunks are related, then both of the chunks will be retrieved, or that one chunk will be there, which is a higher accuracy, which is a higher like similarity with that particular quotient.
Sunny: Let's say we are passing a next question. Yeah, wait, wait, sir. If we are passing a next question, so the second check will not be retrieved from that question because it is not related to that. It was related to the first question. Okay.
Sunny: And if you have a, like, concern that how the memory will be managed, we have a memory management for that. We can, summarize the previous couple of conversations, we can give that context also to the LLM. That is also possible, okay?
bala personal: Okay, I'm talking about the, you know,
bala personal: ingestion by ingestion, sir, in the ingestion pipeline, when we're ingesting, we are generating embedding, embedding, further chunks, right? So, there.
bala personal: We're individually processing, it is a parallel processing. We are individually generating the embeddings for each chunk. So I'm storing into DynamoDB, sorry, storing into VectorDB or whatever, DBFS or whatever.
bala personal: You were trying to say on the retrieval, it's going Right, sir?
Sunny: Yeah, I'm talking about the retrieval part. I will show you the practical, you will get that, okay? So wait for some more classes, you will be getting that.
bala personal: Yeah, one more, you know, let's say if I… if my organization has, you know, millions of images, sir, okay? So, the RAG is built on top of images.
bala personal: So, let's say if a user asks, hey, create me a… out of…
bala personal: generate a new image out of a million images we trained on. So, is it going to do, sir, RAG?
Sunny: Oh, right, we can build the RAG-based, image-based drive also.
Sunny: It… you… you can ju… see, generate the image is not the way. Basically, we can, get that image, okay, and we can showcase image as output. That is possible.
bala personal: But it is not going to create a new image out of…
Sunny: No.
Sunny: Not a new me, that is a different, that will be the different model, okay?
Sunny: Diffusion model will have to be used over there.
bala personal: Thank you, sir.
Sunny: Now, next question is… Sunil, what's your question?
sunil: Hello?
sunil: Oh.
Sunny: Yeah, sorry.
sunil: I have, like, one question regarding this,
sunil: pipeline. So, this ingestion is, like, only one time, right? Like, once we have uploaded documents, there's a policy document. There's some policies keep changing monthly, or there's a pricing document changing monthly.
sunil: And, so monthly, like, we can update our vector database, and then…
sunil: We have only receiver pipeline, right?
sunil: I mean…
sunil: user will query, he send the query, and query will go to the vector database, and from the vector database, it will put to the LLM.
sunil: Making a context and the prompt and then going to the LLM, right?
sunil: So, our… our…
sunil: It is happening like this, like, every time, let's say, there are multiple policy documents, or there are different departments also, but let's say companies have only one chat box. So every time, let's say, one customer sends some query.
sunil: Based on that, some document will be picked, and then Primarily start from the ingestion.
Sunny: Mmhm No, ingestion pipeline is a different pipeline.
Sunny: Okay, so you will keep that, both pipelines separate one, but that would be the decoupled pipeline. Ingion would be from the different pipeline, so the database will be managed, and the retrieval and the generation pipeline would be the different, okay?
sunil: So, most of the cases, or, I mean, always, injection happens like.
sunil: not so frequently, I mean, whenever is needed.
Sunny: Oh, whenever is needed, then only it will be applied.
sunil: Okay, got it, got it.
sunil: And the second is not a question, but nowadays, like, we are hearing a lot of, in terms of agentic development, agent harness, skills.
sunil: So, we'll also… we'll also explain, or maybe cover in your… like, how we can build a skill.
Sunny: Mmhm.
sunil: Oh.
sunil: In the upcoming session, we look forward to this.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, I will… I can show you that, okay.
sunil: Okay, yeah.
Sunny: Scleranol. See, just, just, just, these just are the fancy term.
Sunny: Which is, being invented by some LinkedIn post, or some, like, the YouTube folks, okay? Maybe in some of the blog, they've catched up this term, and then they have created a video. And that video, like, people are watching, okay, it's Kilhar… these are some fancy terms, sir. Nothing is there.
Sunny: Okay. Okay. If you will read about the Agent R, then what is it? What do you think about it? Tell me now.
sunil: what I understood, like, there are multiple skills being built, and each No.
Sunny: How the… see, how the agent is doing the planning?
Sunny: Okay, that is a agent harness, the control layers of the agent. User input, agent planning, tool selection, tool execution, memory, error handling, final response. That is a, like, harness of the agent.
Sunny: Okay.
sunil: Okay.
Sunny: The full system that controls everything safely, that is agent RMS. Now tell me, are we not going to be learning this in our agent system? Someone has written something, let's say it's from IBM, from Microsoft, they have released one block over the official page.
sunil: And when.
Sunny: New term harness. Now someone blogger or some YouTuber have picked that term and created a video and someone has posted over the LinkedIn multiple times. So that is agent harness. That is what is happening, sir. And people are thinking this is a different concept, new concept. No.
Sunny: Nothing.
Sunny: Okay.
sunil: Okay, what I understood, this is mostly driven by the skills, like, where they're, pushing emphasis. Like, agent harness is something, like, not building an agent, but, it…
sunil: Keep building the skills, so your agent will harness those skills, like, kind of reusable skills.
sunil: One example, like you're giving here, no? Parsing. Maybe there may be one skill being developed by, parsing or some skill for, let's say.
sunil: Calculating, on optimization, some… something like that.
sunil: Are you talking…
Sunny: Talking about the claw skills, is it?
sunil: No, no, no. So again, specific.
Sunny: Okay, specific action is that skill only, right? So, see, if specific capability or the action which is taken by the agent, that is a…
Sunny: Skills.
sunil: -H.
Sunny: Okay.
sunil: Okay.
Sunny: So, let's say LM.
sunil: A tool, yeah?
Sunny: Yeah, tool is an external function, external functionality, right? A skill is what? It's a predefined abilities, workflow, basically.
Sunny: Right? Which we are going to be built using what? The complete tools, prompts, and the logic. That's it. Nothing else.
Sunny: Okay.
sunil: Okay, okay, okay, so this is, like, something reusable that can be used in agents.
Sunny: Complete task capability, that's it, that's a skill.
sunil: Okay, hopefully, yeah, once you're covered, then obviously we can visualize it.
sunil: Useful for our practical also.
sunil: Enjoy yours.
sunil: Thank you. Thank you, Sunny.
Sunny: Thank you.
Sunny: Okay, so needless one. Guys, just give me one more minute, I'll take another questions, okay? Wait.
Sunny: Mmhm
Sunny: Okay, so again, let's start the doubt session.
Sunny: So, Anil, what's your doubt?
Anil Chaurasiya: Hey, Sunny. Actually, I have, one small query on fine tuning versus rag, when to apply fine tuning and when to apply rag. I have one small use case. I will keep it short.
Anil Chaurasiya: I have, for example, 50,000 of,
Anil Chaurasiya: movie content or VOD content. I want to make it, linear live channel, like, that will be…
Anil Chaurasiya: Like, sequence of VOD will be played, kind of one playlist I want to make.
Anil Chaurasiya: So, I want to build one AI-based scheduler, so it's like small POC tasks.
Anil Chaurasiya: So in this, I have all the metadata for
Anil Chaurasiya: all the VOD assets. Basically, all the media files, have
Anil Chaurasiya: all the metadata, like, actor, director, and I have your ship data also for those assets, like, for, India region, these are the assets.
Anil Chaurasiya: are playing most, so we are getting more viewership. So ask is, we want to build a channel so that we can get more user retention on the channel, and more revenue, so we are inserting ad also on that channel.
Anil Chaurasiya: So my quick question is, shall I proceed with the fine-tuning in this case, or shall I apply the access? I already have all the metadata inserted in my storage, like S3 or something like that.
Anil Chaurasiya: So… So, are you able to connect the dots, or any question on this?
Sunny: Yeah, so you can, what you can do, na?
Sunny: But… See, what I can say, you have 1500 BOD asset, right?
Anil Chaurasiya: Right, right.
Sunny: Now, what you can do… See, use RAG for this one.
Anil Chaurasiya: Okay.
Sunny: Okay. Use RAG for content metadata retrieval in the explanation. Okay. Right?
Sunny: Then, this one. Use recommendation ranking.
Sunny: model, and just do some optimization logic for the scheduling and all. Got it? Okay. Fine-tuning is optional here, it is not required. I would suggest you can build this entire system with the RAG itself. Use any good model, and build it using the RAG. Okay.
Anil Chaurasiya: Yeah, so, already, we have some free model in my office, like, Gauss 4.0, something like that, it is already available. So, this is basically text-based processing, it needs basically a list-based JSON file, where we'll get some unique programming.
Sunny: That's what I'm saying. RAG actually is just a concept where you are going to be talking about the retrieval and all that shit, right? But you will have to orchestrate this entire system, the scheduling and all everything, right? RAG will not do that by itself, okay?
Anil Chaurasiya: Right.
Sunny: The core concept of the RAG is basically to retrieve it to enhance the context of the LLM and all, then generate the system. So I would suggest you design this entire system, use the LangGraph orchestration, where basically one of the branch is performing this RAG, other branch is doing the scheduling and all, okay, and then now you are going to combine the entire result and all, got it? So use the LangGraph orchestration over here.
Sunny: You can build that system.
Sunny: Understood.
Anil Chaurasiya: Okay, okay. Actually, I was thinking the same, but earlier I… actually, we have… I'm following, your… all the lectures, so earlier I was suggested fine-tuning, then, my senior suggested to go for, you know, VectorDB, where we can store all the information.
Anil Chaurasiya: Nope.
Sunny: That's what I'm.
Anil Chaurasiya: Okay. Okay, I'll just explore more, and if anything…
Sunny: Explore LangGraph, orchestrate the sensors, enter a solution of the LangGraph, give the name as Agentic RAG, okay?
Sunny: And then different… created different branches. One is for the retrieval, and one is for the scheduling constant and all, one is for the other scoring formula, one is for getting the data, preparing the data, set data and all, something like that, right? So likewise, you can design the entire system, okay?
Anil Chaurasiya: Yeah, yeah, definitely, Sunny. Thank you so much. I'll just explore this, and I'll keep you posted in case, you know.
Anil Chaurasiya: I stuck somewhere.
Sunny: Sure, sure. Thank you.
Anil Chaurasiya: Thank you, thanks so much.
Sunny: Yep.
Sunny: Okay, Tej, what's your doubt? Please go ahead with the.
Tej: So, Sunny, if you can pull that diagram where you were showing the whole RAG
Tej: Set up, right?
Sunny: -H
Sunny: Just a second.
Tej: I think you just passed later.
Sunny: Yeah, this is the.
Tej: Yeah, this one, this one, you're right, yeah, yeah. So, yeah, this is very good, right? I understand the difference between the regular querying of LLM versus the RAG, right? So, in short, RAG, you query, then when you query, what it is doing is, it's actually going to the data source, right? You know.
Tej: capturing the additional, information, and it is augmenting the query that we gave, right, by adding context.
Tej: And then it is it is feeding the LLM. Right? So in this bottom right hand corner, you see there's user query plus context plus custom instruction. Right? Where is custom instruction coming from?
Sunny: You will be writing that customer instruction, no?
Sunny: let's say you have a context, you have a user question. You can give some custom instruction, like, okay, summarize this information in that way, answer only this specific question… this specific answer, put some more, like,
Tej: Caught in my r.
Sunny: To this side. You can write this customer instruction, okay?
Tej: Like, if you can give me an example, like, you will get that in the upcoming session, you will get that.
Tej: You're talking about this HR information, right? Which can…
Sunny: No, no, I will show you practically, just wait for some time, I'll show you that practically, okay?
Tej: Okay. And so, you know, again, RAG is always coming in the context of RAG versus fine-tuning, right? So, so this is something that you…
Tej: As a company, you decide this.
Tej: at the setup time itself, right? It is not like…
Tej: You don't decide on the fl.
Sunny: See, it is not like that. Fine-tuning is a different thing, RAG is a different thing. Okay, we have enough capable model, on top of that, we can build up this RAG system.
Sunny: RAIC system is very popular than the fine-tuning, because the training is required over there.
Sunny: Until an analyst company don't want their own model, their own world… they don't want until their own knowledge-enhanced model, we don't do the fine-tuning, we don't do the training, we don't involve into the training, okay? So don't think that the RAG versus fine-tuning always, no. Again, I'm saying we have enough capable model.
Sunny: Where we can provide the context to the model, and based on that, we can generate the answer. This is what ChatGPT is doing, no sir?
Sunny: Right?
Tej: Just tell me…
Sunny: No.
Tej: If the model is good enough, instead we can just give context and…
Sunny: Aha, you can give the context. Correct.
Tej: Right? Okay.
Sunny: just tell me one thing. You are using ChatGPT, right? ChatGPT is able to provide any sort of answer, right?
Tej: -H.
Sunny: the latest news or whatever news. Now, how it is doing that? Because the reasoning of the model is a very good, it is a very capable model. So even though you are going to provide a small context to the model, it is able to generate the answer based on that, right? Let's say tomorrow you are going to the doctor.
Sunny: Okay, they are prescribing you some medicine. You are putting that prescription over the chat GPT, and you're asking something. It is able to give the answer or not, correct?
Tej: Right, right.
Sunny: Oh.
Tej: So, so you're saying that's not.
Sunny: Basically…
Tej: The context, yeah, that is, that context is adding is nothing is called RAG, right?
Sunny: Oh, got it.
Tej: Okay. So so now on this, can you also help me understand the inferencing part? Right. I get confused with inferencing. So in this picture is adding this context generation.
Sunny: Only is called the inferencing.
Tej: generation is inferencing or adding the context is inferencing.
Sunny: Generating is inferencing. Inferencing means prediction. So in the generation only it is doing the prediction, next token prediction, correct? The generation is called the inferencing, okay?
Tej: Okay. So whether it happens through RAG or fine tuning, whatever it is, ultimately, when the LLM when the model generates the data, that is called the inferencing. Got it.
Sunny: Correct.
Tej: Okay, yeah, thanks, Annie. That's all from my side.
Sunny: Think.
Sunny: Okay, Baba, what's your doub.
Vaibhav Dawande: Hey, hi, Sunny. I have 3 questions.
Vaibhav Dawande: First is related to assignments.
Vaibhav Dawande: So, I have used the base model, which you have used in Unsloth session.
Sunny: Okay.
Vaibhav Dawande: And, I have used the domain in, like, course, doubts assistant.
Sunny: So…
Vaibhav Dawande: I just asked those questions for, non-instant.
Vaibhav Dawande: For instruction dataset, like, input and output.
Vaibhav Dawande: So, I have asked the same questions, too.
Vaibhav Dawande: Copilot Chatbot. May I can use the… that, model which I have used for this? Like, wait…
Vaibhav Dawande: That, what I can say?
Vaibhav Dawande: That, what was the name?
Vaibhav Dawande: T, alpa, alpa something you have used, right? Alpa ka.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Vaibhav Dawande: So, my base, my domain is totally different, and in that alpaca, the inputs are related to, pharma. Inputs are… questions are related to pharma, and outputs are also related to pharma.
Vaibhav Dawande: So, I have used the same. I have used… asked the questions. May I can use the tiny LLAMA model for base model?
Vaibhav Dawande: An instruction purpose, may I can use the… That alpaca format.
Vaibhav Dawande: But the domains are totally different, right? The codes doubt.
Vaibhav Dawande: Data sets, means the coarsed out assistant is different. Input and output, insta, instruction, input and output is totally different.
Vaibhav Dawande: So, the chatbot is saying you can use, absolutely use this data, but, I'm not sure, is this the hallucinating,
Vaibhav Dawande: Or this is the correct or not, that actually are my questions to you.
Sunny: Sir, show me the solution, I can give you the better answer.
Sunny: Just by seeing the solution.
Vaibhav Dawande: It doesn'.
Sunny: Related to what? It is your personal project, or what so?
Vaibhav Dawande: No, no, no, this is related to your assignment only. Just based on…
Sunny: Assignment, we can ask me later on, or just build it, okay? Build in that timeline, just do the brainstorming and all. Because, see, if I'm solving the assignment behalf on you, then what will be the meaning of that? So, I'll provide the solution and all, but just do some more brainstorming on it, okay?
Vaibhav Dawande: Okay, so no problem. Then I will… My second question is related to that research paper. You have two or three times you told me if you want to research any paper, so you can upload on any chatbot. So they will give you the
Vaibhav Dawande: exams, related information regarding research paper. So what is the behind process of that? I mean, what actually, the LLM do?
Vaibhav Dawande: So, he will get that context of that, all the research paper, and they will give you the exact answer which you asked related to this.
Vaibhav Dawande: This is the related to RAG or what actually LLM do behind this.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, see, what happened… Okay, let me draw that architecture, just a second.
Sunny: Can you see my screen?
Vaibhav Dawande: Just a minute.
Vaibhav Dawande: I'm not able to see any screen from, I don't know… Why?
Sunny: It is visible now, right?
Vaibhav Dawande: Sir, I really don't know, from, I was
Vaibhav Dawande: It's not able… I'm not able to see any
Vaibhav Dawande: No problem, you just, explain me, orally, I will understand.
Sunny: Yeah, so that's… now, can you see?
Vaibhav Dawande: No, sir, really not.
Sunny: Okay.
Vaibhav Dawande: I don't know.
Sunny: So, yeah, so what happened now? Let's say you uploaded a document, okay? So after that, what it is doing? It is doing some data parsing.
Sunny: Right? Okay. It is extracting the data from your document. Let's say you uploaded a PDF, it took the data from it, out of it, okay? Now, that particular data directly is being given to the LLM model. Now, let's say if you have used any sort of a chat assistant.
Sunny: ChatGPT, Cloud Chat Assistant, Meta Chat Assistant, or Perplexity, whatever, right? It is performing the same kind of process. First, it takes your data, it pass the data from there, it provide to the LLM, okay, with some specific set of instruction that this is a data, summarized data, whatever, or means whatever you are asking. Getting my point, right? And then LLM is generating answer based on that.
Sunny: Understood That's it. That's the simplest process happening in the bac Okay.
Vaibhav Dawande: Okay, my third is, third question is related to the, new upcoming, jobs is creating related to that, if, I mean, I just heard these things on YouTube, so, go to,
Vaibhav Dawande: Go to something kind of new job is created means the in what is the main behind question is if I'm a I'm a good I'm a AI engineer, sorry, junior engineer, and I will go to any particular company.
Vaibhav Dawande: Which… where already they have a website. So I can build my, co-pilot on this website. So this kind of, things, are you going to…
Vaibhav Dawande: Learning, I mean, speeches.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Vaibhav Dawande: Means, this is my question. I'm asking you.
Sunny: Copilot, yes, you can build a Copilot. Actually, what that Copilot is doing again behind the Copilot, it's an Agentic system, correct? So if you know how to build that Agentic system, how to build any Agentic system, then you can build that Copilot also according to the requirement.
Sunny: No, I'.
Vaibhav Dawande: I'm asking about the, no, no, I'm asking about if, if I'm a, if I have a website, XYZ website, I have to integrate.
Sunny: it, you can.
Vaibhav Dawande: LL.
Sunny: They're also, sir, right? So, how to integrate? Nothing, you just will be writing some other module inside the same code base?
Sunny: Okay, they will provide you the website code base, you will clone that feature… you will clone that code inside your system, you will create a separate feature branch related to the copilot, related to the AI assistant, you are doing your coding over there, okay? And then you can integrate that feature. It is easy.
Sunny: Get a word for it.
Vaibhav Dawande: I'm not sure how to do that, but are you going to teach us.
Sunny: Ha! I will teach you the project and all, you will… with that, you will get an idea, okay?
Vaibhav Dawande: Okay, thank you so much, Sunny.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you.
Sunny: Okay, next out,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Hello, am I audible?
Sunny: Yeah, Amol, please go ahead.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Yeah, my question is, so, so in, so, I mean, when we have a RDG attached to the LLM, and there's a, we have a RDG infrastructure, then suppose the query has, no relevance to the RDG data, then still will it always try to search it into the RDG before the
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: sending the LLM query, or does it depend on… or do we add some condition that
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Like, some kind of similarity of the contact, of the question to the Aditya data.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Then only to, I mean, does it always look up into the RDG database, when we send the query?
Sunny: Check, actually, let's say, let's say we are getting user query, okay?
Sunny: So, what we can do, we can check, is this query related to our knowledge base or not?
Sunny: Okay? If the query is related to the knowledge base, then we can search the database, we can search the vector database.
Sunny: If that is not related to our knowledge base, we can simply answer or answer. Normally we can reject that, we can reject that query, okay? Or we can route somewhere else for this, this kind of a specific query which is not related to our database. For that, again, we can design some specific answer that is not relevant to this database, is not a relevant query, ask something else, something like that.
Sunny: So that kind of orchestration we can do. Got it?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay. I mean, like, suppose… I mean, like, though I don't have a deep knowledge of agents, but I think in case of agents, like, we have tools, right? So to… and in the tools that we've mentioned some…
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: some description in the tool function signature regarding the source. So that way, the agent gets to know whether that tool is useful for that particular query, right?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: So similarly, is there a, like a, like, do we have similar way, like some
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Some, function… some,
Sunny: Yeah, like this also we can do, even we can write some deterministic logic also, that is also fine. Got it?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, okay. Means, means we can give some, some description regarding the Avijay database for the LLM that, that only in, only if the query matches to this particular topic, then only look into it.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Oh. And then, and then route it into the…
Sunny: Correct. Use the similarity search, regex expression, deterministic search, fuzzy logic, anything, whatever you wanted to use.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, means when we send a query, it does not have to always, approach the RDG first,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: And they don't need… No.
Sunny: Okay.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: It can bypass the RDG, suppose the context of question is totally not related to the RDG database, right?
Sunny: Correct. It can buy…
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, and secondly, my question was, so, this RDG and the AI agents, so, are we going to cover the, the enterprise-level production pipeline deployment,
Sunny: What do you mean, like, the enterprise level deploy.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: I mean, I have… Miss Ivan, I don't know, but Miss, I have heard somewhere that
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: like, some courses, they cover only, like, some high level, and… but the enterprise production pipelines are built complex, or something like that, so…
Sunny: Jesus.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Wait.
Sunny: this deployment pipeline and all, and all that, right? This everything is being… is being designed according to the requirement.
Sunny: Okay. Now, agar aap merko bologe kalko, ki sani ek sah deployment kar do, Google ya sah. Toh mak kaise kar paan wah bata. Kalk aap merko pucho ya ki bhai mere
Sunny: Saudo solo log use karete ett nablan ka user bais dong, ma.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Look, look, look, ma'am.
Sunny: Deployment ki sari services voida thi hai.
Sunny: Okay. Okay, Mr.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, okay, fine.
Sunny: Ha, so that is also a mirror of that particular enterprise-related deployment pipeline only. Let's say when I have used… So, from that perspective, you will have to understand. Got it?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, but the main concept will remain the same, just that this scaling… I think then,
Sunny: The scaling would be the difference.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, right.
Sunny: Concept would be the same over here.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, so I think then that would come under the scaling of, like, the scaling of applications type and… Huh.
Sunny: Scaling and the deployment is a subjective thing, right? Let's say tomorrow you went in some company. I have shown you one deployment pipe. I have used the AWS. In the AWS, I have used the, let's say, AWS, this one, ECS, okay, Fargate. I deployed one application with that managed Kubernetes services.
Sunny: In your service, in your enterprises also, you are doing the same thing, but there, the application is a little big, bigger one, and along with that EKS, along with that managed services, you're going to be using other services also, surrounding to that.
Sunny: Okay, so that the different exposure could be there, but if you're fundamentalist, you know how to write that YAML file, how to write the configuration, how to perform the CI-CD, anywhere you can do it, correct?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: But then my question is, like, but for the same amount of users, like, suppose if my… if the, if the company industry requires the same amount of users.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: As our application is being built, then will the same application work in a, in a production industry pipeline also, right?
Sunny: See, sir, it might work, but we had some ad hoc challenges in our production, okay, and it is subject to the application also.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Swe.
Sunny: tomorrow, you are getting some concurrency issues, some downtime, some this, that, whatever, right? So that, you will have to understand. See, cloud…
Sunny: deployment, basically, it is inheriting from the DevOps knowledge. Getting my point, right? You should have the DevOps knowledge. If you're sitting with any guy who is having a good DevOps experience, then you can learn the cloud deployment better.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Right, right, okay. So suppose if we complement this course with additional DevOps as well as system design knowledge, like, which is not related to the agents, then that would be a big, that would be complete enterprise thing, right? Miss, we don't know… Miss, Miss, what I mean to say is, like, suppose, like, we have system design and these courses in Udemy as well, so…
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: If we complement that knowledge with this… with the deployment of this course, and suppose DevOps knowledge as well, then that would be a complete
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: End-to-end, more kind of,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: enterprise-level kind of thing, right? What I mean to say is, we don't need to look out more for AI concepts. All AI concepts will be taught in the course, only the additional DevOps or the system design concepts, which are independent of the Agentic AI domain.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: If we, if we learn that, then we are good with in, in that respect only.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: And so…
Sunny: Yes, got it, got it, right.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, okay. So we are not leaving out anything as far as Agentic AI is concerned in this course. We are covering everything, but if we want to have more kind of scaling and those things, which are independent concepts, then that we can, just, learn and, and apply
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay. Okay, fine, fine. Yeah, that's… Got it. Yeah, yeah. Okay. Thanks. Thanks again.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you.
Sunny: Your next talk is…
Rajib Saha: Bye.
Akshay: Hi.
Sunny: Yeah, with,
Rajib Saha: I do, yes.
Sunny: Akshay, Dinesh, Rajiv, anyone?
Krish S: Sandy, this is Kr.
Sunny: Wait, wait, Krishna, I'm coming to you. Yeah, Rajiv, first you go, then there is that.
Rajib Saha: Yeah, actually, Sunny.
Sunny: Mmm.
Rajib Saha: I mean… I'm a professor in a GNEI and Agentic AI, but I'm actually experienced in like
Rajib Saha: We'll do 14 years experience in development section.
Rajib Saha: But I'm learning in Hindi guy, and
Rajib Saha: Gen AI, but I am shifted to, Gen DK and, Gen AI field.
Rajib Saha: I am not sure how I apply this job.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Sunny: So, see, I have published one podcast, okay, which is, like, similar to your situation only. Just watch out that. It is 40 to 45 minutes of podcast.
Sunny: Where someone is from the different IT background, who is, like, transitioning into the Senior Gen AI and the Agentic AI role, okay? So that podcast can give you the detailed knowledge.
Sunny: Right? And then, if you have any sort of a question, you can ask me in the next session, okay? In the next out session. But it is highly recommended, you can watch out that, I'm sharing the link in the chat, just go.
Rajib Saha: I'm just, I'm just asking one question, please.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Rajib Saha: Actually, actually,
Rajib Saha: Actually, I'm applying, somewhere in, through the NOC, right? But, I get a call. When I'm getting call, then everyone asking that, you are experienced or not. I'm, just I completed the RAG section, I can build some little bit, RAG application, like.
Rajib Saha: weather forecast, or hotel booking system, or, like, that type of application. I think I create a, application like that, video, I get a video, 10, 10 to 12 hours video, and I extract that text and create a chat application from there.
Rajib Saha: And that type of application, I mean, A PDF, read and… I'm.
Rajib Saha: Create application from the… I've… PDF.
Sunny: Mmh.
Rajib Saha: The type of application I build in my, local machine.
Rajib Saha: But I did not, hit the, application, industry oriented, I think.
Rajib Saha: So I, I have a competition that I, how I take the preparation and how it'll show that I am two or three experience guys, how I apply this job.
Sunny: So, that's what I'm saying, no? So, see, if we are able to learn something from the same person which… who recently did this thing, right? So, we'll get a better clarity, correct?
Rajib Saha: So…
Sunny: As I advise, what I can say, build some 2-3 production-grade GenAI project, not just that simple notebook or the basic application, RAG agent, tool, API, whatever you're doing, okay? Update your resume with a better positioning. Do not write only learning GenAI or this, that, right?
Rajib Saha: in your.
Sunny: write your existing, development experience with the GenAI implementation experience. Getting my point. So you will have to influence to the interview with your knowledge.
Sunny: Okay. But what kind of knowledge you have, or what kind of work, basically, you have done, and how, basically, you can adopt this Agentic and the Generative AI, that kind of thing you will have to do, right? So that's where I'm saying, just watch out this video, it will help you a lot. Generally, I'm saying…
Rajib Saha: Where I, where I get this video?
Sunny: I have sent you the chat.
Rajib Saha: Okay.
Sunny: And, if any question is remaining, you can discuss in the next class. Got it?
Rajib Saha: Okay, okay, okay, thank you.
Rajib Saha: Thank you, Sam.
Sunny: Thank you.
Sunny: Yeah, Dinesh, please go ahead with the question.
Dinesh Babu Bashyam: So, the thing is,
Sunny: Mmh.
Dinesh Babu Bashyam: Regarding to this project, So…
Dinesh Babu Bashyam: should we create the files on the windows laptop and then train the this thing on the collab? Or is it the procedure that we should be following, sir.
Sunny: For which one?
Dinesh Babu Bashyam: For this project, which, we are given, right?
Dinesh Babu Bashyam: For the project.
Sunny: Assignment, assignment.
Dinesh Babu Bashyam: Assignment, yes, the assignment.
Sunny: No, you can do in the collab itself, no? And then download after collab, you can train the collab… train, the model, you know, everything over the collab, okay? And then download the file in the local itself, just to upload it over the GitHub, that's it.
Dinesh Babu Bashyam: Okay.
Sunny: Okay.
Dinesh Babu Bashyam: Thank you, Sid.
Sunny: The same approach which I was taking, you can take.
Dinesh Babu Bashyam: Okay.
Dinesh Babu Bashyam: Thank you.
Sunny: Yeah, thanks.
Sunny: Yeah, Krishna, please go ahead. Akshay, Krishna, anyone is there? Guys, if you have done that, please below… yeah, please lower the hand, because it creates confusion. Yeah, Krishna.
Krish S: Hi, Sunny. So, thank you for the RAG overview today. I have two questions. So, I'm trying to build…
Krish S: something, like, you know, on the side project, and I'm using, like, basically planning to use, rather, RAG to process, like, contracts.
Krish S: So, I have multiple clients, so each client has their own, you know, attributes in those documents and all that stuff. So, my first question is, how do I,
Krish S: concurrently process these users so that, you know, I'm not accessing incorrect data, you know, based on the prompts or other information that I supply to the rack.
Krish S: And the second question is.
Krish S: if I have the document for a single client, rather multiple documents for the single client, how do I kind of establish that relationship so that, you know, I'm not losing the context across, like, say, 4 or 5 documents that I need to get this information from?
Sunny: Yeah, hello, can you hear me?
Krish S: Yeah, yeah, I can hear you.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah. So, what you were asking… Sorry, I missed… you were asking, like, how to concurrently process, right?
Krish S: Correct. Like, if I have multiple documents using the same VectorDB, but, you know, different document, different attributes for different users, but obviously they're using all the same VectorDB. So how do I ensure that I know I'm not, like…
Sunny: So what we can do now, you can basically create a separate, separate index.
Sunny: Okay. In the vector database, basically, you can create a multiple index, let's say for the client A document index A, client B document index B, client C document index C.
Sunny: Right? So whenever client asks a question, search only in the index. Okay? So this is a strong isolation which you can create.
Sunny: Getting my point.
Krish S: Got it, got it. Okay, so I kind of stored that as a met.
Sunny: Oh.
Krish S: Link to that session, and then…
Sunny: That is also you can do, separate namespace you can provide as of in the form of metadata, okay? Okay. So many vector databases supported the namespace, or you can, discrimination do with… you can do the discrimination based on the metadata also, right?
Sunny: Now, concurrency part, basically, see, if user is uploading the document, you are storing a file anywhere, okay, and now you are creating an ingestion job and all, so what you can do for that, you can use a celery task, you know, celery.
Sunny: C E L E R Y.
Sunny: Oh…
Krish S: Okay, I'm not so technical, but I'll dig into it.
Sunny: Just check with that. Actually, it's for the… I implemented the concurrent process only. Everything you can process in the parallel itself. Celery plus Ladies, use this one. I have used in my one of the projects for the faster processing, and this is very much required for the bigger document, where you have 10 to 15 to 20 to 100 documents. The Celery document will help you a lot. So just ask to the Cloud or ChatGPT to implement the Celery in your project, okay, for the parallel processing.
Krish S: Okay.
Sunny: Got it.
Krish S: Okay, perfect.
Sunny: Yep.
Krish S: And the second question is, if I have multiple documents for the same user, and I have to link and establish one context, how do I go about…
Sunny: So for that, I think metadata will help you, sir. Metadata will help you. So just, collect the, the information, okay? Client ID or something like that. You can provide the client ID, user ID, okay, document ID. Based on that, basically, you can make a disk mission. Got it?
Krish S: Okay. I read somewhere, like, maybe graph, whatever, rag…
Sunny: Make a too complex, solution, sir, okay? If you can do everything with a simple solution, why to make that graph and all, okay? So…
Krish S: I see. I see. OK, good. OK, thank you, Sunny.
Sunny: Thank you.
Sunny: Okay, next out is,
Akshay: Bye.
Sunny: Hi, Krishna. Hi, A.
Akshay: Yes, I have a very quick question. So, like, I am a new student into AI, and I've been following your lecture since a while. So I just wanted to ask you, like, what are the day-to-day tasks, like, as a GIS developer when I was, so I had a consistent task of, you know, data annotation, cleaning. They were using this for a recommendation system.
Akshay: So, I want to know, like, what an AI engineer does in his day-to-day life.
Sunny: It depends on the project, sir. Okay.
Sunny: So, if you're working as a AI engineer in any sort of a project, right? So, what you can do over there, let's say, if you're working in any,
Sunny: RAG projects, got it? So there, maybe you will be setting up the vector databases, you are going to retrieve the information from the vector, this one, from the documents, right? Or maybe you are going to be write a good prompt over there, you are going to be configure the good prompt.
Sunny: Okay? Or maybe you are going to be focused on the retrieval side, to make a, like, the… to generate a good response from the LLM. So that kind of task you would be doing. So first, you are doing this as a POC to showcase the good result to the business.
Sunny: And the result is being approved, then you're going into the production, okay, in the full-fledged development phase. And there again, maybe your team might increase, and you have lots of other developers also, and you are going to be, contributing with them, okay? With those developers, you're dividing the tasks.
Sunny: So, as an AI developer, basically, as an AI engineer, majority of the time, you are going to be involved with the data pipeline, to setting up the data pipeline, to write a good prompt, okay? If you're a senior folk, then you are going to be managing the entire project as a lead, as an architect. We are focusing on the database side.
Sunny: Or the API side, or the entire system side, okay, whether, how to design that system effectively, okay, how the pre-processing, the concurrent processing is happening, okay, onto that side. Okay, how to accommodate the new requirement from the business, you are focusing onto that as well, okay? So these kind of tasks you are doing. So development will remain the development only. There, some more, AI stuff is going to be integrated in the project itself.
Sunny: Okay.
Akshay: Yes, like, my thing was, like, I want to be doing something which is, like, I want to be specialized in track, so that's why I was asking what kind of sections do we work, so I want to, like, be specialized in one section, or I want to be, you know.
Akshay: very perfect in one section, so that in any interviews, I can, you know, perform or tell them about it, or more focus my interview towards it, where I'm more expertise to, or my company is doing the same thing, like, as you said.
Akshay: Might be a retriev.
Sunny: I told you the pipeline, just master that pipeline, that's it. But see, interviewer will not be focused on the one RAG project or something like that, okay? He will look into your overall knowledge.
Sunny: Got it. So how good with your cloud-specific knowledge? How good with your Agentic knowledge?
Sunny: whether really you did develop something in a real time or not, okay, it would be like that. So don't be focused on one side of things, like retrieval or not, it's not a, like, sufficient one. Got it? So master at least a complete system. That's what I'm saying. Got it?
Akshay: Okay, I need one niche, no? So, I want to focus.
Sunny: Generative AI itself is a niche. Now, inside that also, you are creating a niche, then how it will work, huh?
Akshay: Yes, yes, yes, I got you. And my second question would be, like, I checked your, like, resume structure, so I just wanted to ask you, like.
Akshay: this tech stack, which, like, given in your resume, we don't have, we have some which is, like, fresher, or something which is, like, a coming student should have, so we should focus more on projects, right? So, are we going to perform some projects, like, which we are going to do, or, like, we have some projects which we, I have personally built?
Akshay: So, are you going to tell us, like, what product, like, fully end-to-end pipelines should we showcase that would be more better for the resume, or…
Akshay: You want us to do, like… because I'm currently applying, right? So, I just wanted to know that.
Sunny: So, you are fresher.
Akshay: Yes.
Sunny: So, yeah, if you're fresher, then you can mention my project only, whatever we are doing in the classes, no? You can mention those projects, okay?
Akshay: Okay, like, because pressure in the sight of, like, AI, because I was a GIS engineer earlier, so was handling data structure and stuff, but as an AI engineer, we are, like, we, I hadn't, I had just completed my master's, so I don't have any specific thing, which is, like…
Sunny: Sometimes, Cigna, you can pick my project, you can do some enhancement modification on top of it, you can associate it with a solid business out problem, then mention it in the resume, okay?
Akshay: Okay, fair, fair, fair. That's what it was.
Akshay: Yes, thank you, sir.
Sunny: Thank you.
Sunny: Yeah, hi, Smith, what's your.
Smit: Yeah, hi, Sunny, thank you. So, Sunny, my question was regarding the user input and vector database, right? So, does a user need to have access to the vector database?
Smit: To get the…
Sunny: No, no, no, no.
Smit: No, right.
Sunny: Should not have the access altogether.
Smit: Okay, that's perfect. Thank you.
Sunny: Yeah, thanks.
Sunny: Okay, next out is, just a second…
Sunny: Yeah, Ravi, what's your.
Ravi: Yes, sir.
Ravi: Actually, I am your big fan, and I am attending your fall workshop. So, I… currently, I have a question that is, from the LLM ops batch. Okay, sir?
Sunny: Mmhm.
Ravi: I, want to share my screen, could you please allow me?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, you can share.
Ravi: One option is not available for sharing. Yeah.
Ravi: Sorry, may I already go?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, you're audible. You can.
Ravi: So, I have, started your, one, project. That is, basically e-commerce product. Could you share my screen, please?
Sunny: Yeah, it is visible.
Ravi: So, here, I have implemented each and everything.
Ravi: In EDL pipeline, and I am successfully able to run this pipeline, okay?
Sunny: Mmhm.
Ravi: Can't see here.
Ravi: But when I am going to see the,
Ravi: She used to be 5, okay?
Sunny: Mmm.
Ravi: So, I am not getting the data, and when I am going to check my vector database, as well, I'm not able to see the reports.
Sunny: -
Sunny: Okay, I think there is some issue with the scrapping only, because Flipkart is day-to-day updating their tags and all, so that's why it is not able to fetch the data, okay, from the Flipkart itself. So, we'll have to check that, what is the current new dev, the tag, okay, dev tag.
Sunny: And then only the data will be coming. So you can do some exercise onto that side, the data scrapping side, and then this pipeline will be working. Got it?
Ravi: So, sir, when I, means, using this one side, right?
Ravi: When I enter here, data, and press enter, so webpage is coming for, Flipkart, okay? And there I can see the product, whatever I am searching from this UI, okay?
Sunny: Oh.
Ravi: But data-wise is not coming, so could you please, tell me that from where should I focus? Like, you are saying that data is scraper.
Sunny: Data scrapping side now, just do one thing, create one notebook out of this data scrapper and check out over there whether you are able to fetch the data or not.
Sunny: Okay, once that experiment is successful, then you can integrate in the end-to-end pipeline, okay?
Ravi: So, from where, basically, I have to focus, sir, here, could you please tell me?
Sunny: From this data scrapper side only.
Sunny: Just focus into this file, okay?
Ravi: So, in this file, like, there is a GitHub review function. So, in this function, I have basically changed something in this.
Ravi: Because, I was not able to run, I was facing some issues, so I have changed, like, here, you have used UC something. UC…
Ravi: You see here a lot.
Ravi: Here I have make the changes. You see, object you are creating.
Ravi: Scrapper underscore dot UI.
Ravi: Okay.
Ravi: And here…
Sunny: We'll have to check, sir. Do one thing, just share with me this file on my mail ID, okay? I'll check it.
Ravi: Okay, sir, please ping your mail ID here.
Sunny: Yeah, sure.
Ravi: Thank you.
Sunny: Thank you, sir
Sunny: Okay, guys, I think I resolved all the doubt now. I'll see you in the next class. Thank you. Bye. Take care.